<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
     xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
     xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Malay Mail - Malaysia]]></title>
        <link>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia</link>
        <description>Malay Mail RSS Feeds: Malaysia</description>
        <dc:language>en</dc:language>
        <dc:creator>Malay Mail</dc:creator>
        <dc:rights>Copyright 2021 Malay Mail</dc:rights>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 10:21:35 +0800</pubDate>
        <atom:link href="https://www.malaymail.com/feed/rss/malaysia" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

                <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tok Mat says Umno polls in August if GE15 not held then]]></title>
            <link>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/12/tok-mat-says-umno-poll-in-august-if-ge15-not-held-then/1965776</link>
            <guid>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/12/tok-mat-says-umno-poll-in-august-if-ge15-not-held-then/1965776</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[KUALA LUMPUR, April 12 — Umno party elections will be held in August this year if the impending general election is not held then, says party deputy president Datuk Seri Mohamad Hasan. Utusan Malaysia reported Mohamad, or more commonly known as...]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
                                <p><figure class="figure  float-left" style="width:800px">
        <img src="https://media2.malaymail.com/uploads/articles/2021/2021-03/umno_Mohamad_Hasan_270321b.jpg" class="figure-img img-fluid rounded" alt="Umno deputy president Datuk Seri Mohamad Hasan arrives at the 2020 Umno annual general meeting in Kuala Lumpur March 27, 2021. ― Picture by Hari Anggara" title="Umno deputy president Datuk Seri Mohamad Hasan arrives at the 2020 Umno annual general meeting in Kuala Lumpur March 27, 2021. ― Picture by Hari Anggara" width='800'  height='533'>
        <figcaption class="figure-caption">Umno deputy president Datuk Seri Mohamad Hasan arrives at the 2020 Umno annual general meeting in Kuala Lumpur March 27, 2021. ― Picture by Hari Anggara</figcaption>
    </figure>
    <div class="clearfix"></div>
    <div>
        <p class="font-italic">Subscribe to our <a class="font-weight-bold" href="https://t.me/themalaymail" target="_blank">Telegram</a> channel for the latest updates on news you need to know.</p>
        <hr/>
    </div><p>KUALA LUMPUR, April 12 — Umno party elections will be held in August this year if the impending general election is not held then, says party deputy president Datuk Seri Mohamad Hasan.</p><p><em>Utusan Malaysia </em>reported Mohamad, or more commonly known as Tok Mat, saying if the elections were to proceed as planned, it will start from the branch level up to leadership posts with the entire process due to take place until the end of this year.</p><p>However, Mohamad stressed that there are no attempts to deliberately delay the elections as the party’s constitution allows up to an 18-month grace period from the original election date in June of this year.</p><p>“The management committee meeting has been conducted and the decision from this meeting will be brought to the coming Umno’s supreme council meeting.</p><p>“The allegations that party elections are being deliberately delayed are simply not true. Party elections are slated to be held in June of this year. According to the (party’s) constitution, we need to conduct the elections immediately.</p><p>“But in the constitution, there is a clause stating that it doesn’t necessarily need to be done immediately because there is an 18-month extended period and there are leeways for the party to analyse and review the current situation,’’ he said to the Malay daily.</p><p>Mohamad further explained that the party elections cannot be held immediately due to Covid-19 concerns and more so for elections at the branch level as all members have the right to be present and it is not possible to limit attendees at 50 per cent capacity.</p><p>“This is because there will be petitions on invalid election meetings and this will raise tensions. This is what we have to avoid.</p><p>However, Mohamad said party elections will be postponed if a general election is held this year.</p><p>Meanwhile, <em>Berita Harian</em> today also quoted Mohamad as stating that he will meet with PAS deputy president Datuk Seri Tuan Ibrahim Tuan Man this week to discuss the statement issued by his party president, Datuk Seri Abdul Hadi Awang that the party has halted seat negotiations with Umno.&nbsp;</p><p>Mohamad also stated that the meet will discuss the status of Muafakat Nasional (MN).</p><p>“It will also touch on Muafakat Nasional’s relationship that is currently ongoing.</p><p>“I have read Hadi’s statement in the media but in MN’s meeting that is chaired along with PAS deputy president recently decided that seat negotiations with both parties are still proceeding.</p><p>“In fact, 50 per cent of it (seat negotiations) have been agreed upon. We have five formulas, which the first have been agreed upon while a second decision is under joint review.</p><p>“I do not want any suggestions to put on hold the seat negotiations but I will ask an explanation from Tuan Ibrahim soon,’’ he said.</p>
            ]]></content:encoded>
                        <dc:creator>Danial Dzulkifly</dc:creator>
                        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 10:21:35 +0800</pubDate>
            <dc:subject>umno,umno party elections,mohamad hasan,ge15,umno</dc:subject>
        </item>
                <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bintulu MP slams entertainment outlet operators for SOP violation]]></title>
            <link>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/12/bintulu-mp-slams-entertainment-outlet-operators-for-sop-violation/1965754</link>
            <guid>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/12/bintulu-mp-slams-entertainment-outlet-operators-for-sop-violation/1965754</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[KUCHING, April 12 — Bintulu MP Datuk Seri Tiong King Sing has slammed proprietors of entertainment outlets in Bintulu, claiming that they continue to operate past the permitted hours by closing the shutters and continuing to serve their customers....]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
                                <p><figure class="figure  float-left" style="width:800px">
        <img src="https://media2.malaymail.com/uploads/articles/2020/2020-07/tiong_king_sing_01072020.jpg" class="figure-img img-fluid rounded" alt="Tiong said enforcement personnel have the authority to suspend operations at these outlets, revoke their business licenses, and even forcibly break into offending premises suspected of violating SOPs. — Picture from Facebook/Muhyiddin Yassin" title="Tiong said enforcement personnel have the authority to suspend operations at these outlets, revoke their business licenses, and even forcibly break into offending premises suspected of violating SOPs. — Picture from Facebook/Muhyiddin Yassin" width='800'  height='534'>
        <figcaption class="figure-caption">Tiong said enforcement personnel have the authority to suspend operations at these outlets, revoke their business licenses, and even forcibly break into offending premises suspected of violating SOPs. — Picture from Facebook/Muhyiddin Yassin</figcaption>
    </figure>
    <div class="clearfix"></div>
    <div>
        <p class="font-italic">Subscribe to our <a class="font-weight-bold" href="https://t.me/themalaymail" target="_blank">Telegram</a> channel for the latest updates on news you need to know.</p>
        <hr/>
    </div><p>KUCHING, April 12 — Bintulu MP Datuk Seri Tiong King Sing has slammed proprietors of entertainment outlets in Bintulu, claiming that they continue to operate past the permitted hours by closing the shutters and continuing to serve their customers.</p><p>Tiong said such outlets had been known to violate the standard operating procedures (SOP) to curb Covid-19 which clearly stated they could not operate past 10pm.</p><p>He also claimed there have been many public complaints against such outlets with some confirmed Covid-19 cases have indeed been traced back to these outlets.</p><p>“These enterprises have refused to acknowledge and see the true situation of the pandemic happening in their own city and to lawfully follow the SOP stipulated by the authorities.</p><p>“I must urge all business operators in Bintulu, no matter what sector they are in, to provide a high degree of cooperation in Covid-19 prevention.</p><p>“If they persist with violating the SOP, they must face the consequences and I will personally ask the police to intervene during their patrols,” he said in a statement today.</p><p>He added that the enforcement personnel have the authority to suspend these outlets, revoke their business licenses, and even forcibly break into offending premises suspected of violating SOP.</p><p>In order to curb the raging pandemic especially in Bintulu now, Tiong said these are the possible tough actions to be applied to SOP flouters.</p><p>“The level of the pandemic is at a level now where no one can afford to be complacent. Only by having a strict compliance to the SOP can everyone’s safety and health be better assured.</p><p>“These rebellious businesses should think deeply about the future. Only by ensuring the entire community’s health and safety can the economy recover. Only when that happens, can normalcy take hold again and life can get better,” he said.</p><p>Tiong even said that in these circumstances, he could suggest to the authorities to raise the conditional movement control order (CMCO) to an enhanced MCO where everyone will face even more inconvenience.</p><p><br />&nbsp;</p>
            ]]></content:encoded>
                        <dc:creator></dc:creator>
                        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 08:19:01 +0800</pubDate>
            <dc:subject>tiong king sing,bintulu,mco violation</dc:subject>
        </item>
                <item>
            <title><![CDATA[With maribantu.my, Muda seeks to show ‘100pc transparency’ possible while doing good]]></title>
            <link>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/12/with-maribantu.my-muda-seeks-to-show-100pc-transparency-possible-while-doin/1965722</link>
            <guid>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/12/with-maribantu.my-muda-seeks-to-show-100pc-transparency-possible-while-doin/1965722</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[KUALA LUMPUR, April 12 — Malaysia United Democratic Alliance (Muda) has launched an online platform called maribantu.my that seeks public cash donations to help unfortunate &amp;nbsp;Malaysians from all backgrounds. The yet-to-be registered political...]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
                                <p><figure class="figure  float-left" style="width:800px">
        <img src="https://media2.malaymail.com/uploads/articles/2021/2021-04/20210409MZ004_muda_maribantu.JPG" class="figure-img img-fluid rounded" alt="Muda members are seen during the launch of maribantu.my in Petaling Jaya on April 9, 2021. — Picture by Miera Zulyana" title="Muda members are seen during the launch of maribantu.my in Petaling Jaya on April 9, 2021. — Picture by Miera Zulyana" width='800'  height='534'>
        <figcaption class="figure-caption">Muda members are seen during the launch of maribantu.my in Petaling Jaya on April 9, 2021. — Picture by Miera Zulyana</figcaption>
    </figure>
    <div class="clearfix"></div>
    <div>
        <p class="font-italic">Subscribe to our <a class="font-weight-bold" href="https://t.me/themalaymail" target="_blank">Telegram</a> channel for the latest updates on news you need to know.</p>
        <hr/>
    </div><p>KUALA LUMPUR, April 12 — Malaysia United Democratic Alliance (Muda) has launched an online platform called maribantu.my that seeks public cash donations to help unfortunate &nbsp;Malaysians from all backgrounds.</p><p>The yet-to-be registered political entity started by and representing young Malaysians hopes to show that it is possible for public charity funds to be managed 100 per cent honestly with every ringgit accounted for.</p><p>“Maribantu.my was created to avoid loopholes and conflicts in the management of public funds collected for charitable activities.</p><p>“This portal is built together with an audit and expenditure tracking mechanism so that every ringgit collected or donated meets the target group,” Selangor Muda vice-president Hilmi Saifullah said at maribantu.my’s launch here last night.</p><p>He explained that the website is designed to enable all donors to track how their donations, no matter how big or small, are used for its intended purpose.</p><p>In a pre-recorded video shown during the launching, Muda president Syed Saddiq Syed Abdul Rahman said maribantu.my is a non-partisan community project that is a step up from the group’s previous financial crowdfunding initiatives to help disaster-struck Malaysians as well as those who found themselves financially strapped in the Covid economy.</p><p>“This is an initiative from Muda and we are ready to cooperate with NGOs and other political parties because we believe that offering donations is not limited to one side.</p><p>“We will guarantee that we will give 100 per cent transparency and honesty to all the donors on this portal. You will have full access to all the paperwork, documentation and financial reports on all of our projects,” the Muar MP explained.</p><p><br />&nbsp;</p>
            ]]></content:encoded>
                        <dc:creator>Shahrin Aizat Noorshahrizam</dc:creator>
                        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 06:01:21 +0800</pubDate>
            <dc:subject>muda party,malaysia united democratic alliance,maribantu.my</dc:subject>
        </item>
                <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bersatu-PAS alliance will strengthen Perikatan, but a GE15 victory? Not so fast, say analysts]]></title>
            <link>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/12/bersatu-pas-alliance-will-strengthen-perikatan-but-a-ge15-victory-not-so-fa/1965721</link>
            <guid>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/12/bersatu-pas-alliance-will-strengthen-perikatan-but-a-ge15-victory-not-so-fa/1965721</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[KUALA LUMPUR, April 12 — The alliance between Islamist party PAS and Parti Pribumi Bersatu Malaysia (Bersatu) may serve to strengthen the flagging Perikatan Nasional (PN) coalition, but the dynamism of its unity will only be seen in the 15th...]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
                                <p><figure class="figure  float-left" style="width:800px">
        <img src="https://media2.malaymail.com/uploads/articles/2018/2018-12/20181229MZ016_ppbm_logo_caps.JPG" class="figure-img img-fluid rounded" alt="Last month, Bersatu and PAS confirmed that they will maintain their political cooperation through PN, well into GE15. — Picture by Miera Zulyana" title="Last month, Bersatu and PAS confirmed that they will maintain their political cooperation through PN, well into GE15. — Picture by Miera Zulyana" width='800'  height='530'>
        <figcaption class="figure-caption">Last month, Bersatu and PAS confirmed that they will maintain their political cooperation through PN, well into GE15. — Picture by Miera Zulyana</figcaption>
    </figure>
    <div class="clearfix"></div>
    <div>
        <p class="font-italic">Subscribe to our <a class="font-weight-bold" href="https://t.me/themalaymail" target="_blank">Telegram</a> channel for the latest updates on news you need to know.</p>
        <hr/>
    </div><p>KUALA LUMPUR, April 12 — The alliance between Islamist party PAS and Parti Pribumi Bersatu Malaysia (Bersatu) may serve to strengthen the flagging Perikatan Nasional (PN) coalition, but the dynamism of its unity will only be seen in the 15th general election, analysts said.</p><p>Those polled by <em>Malay Mail</em>&nbsp;opined that the situation remains too fluid for them to predict whether the cooperation between the two parties could scupper Umno-Barisan Nasional (BN) and Pakatan Harapan’s (PH) chances at the polls.</p><p>Shazwan Mustafa Kamal, a senior associate with political risk and public policy consultancy Vriens &amp; Partners, believes that Bersatu and PAS alone may not have enough star appeal to win the next national polls, and would need more allies down the road.</p><p>“Bersatu and PAS’ commitment to each other will help strengthen PN, given Umno’s recent decision to formally quit working with Bersatu in GE15. For one, the seat negotiations between Bersatu and PAS would likely be less complicated than with Umno.</p><p>“Bersatu doesn’t have traction or a stake in the key states that PAS is in — Kedah, Kelantan, Terengganu, and to some extent, Perlis. Umno, on the other hand, has a stake in these states.</p><p>“But an alliance between the two may not be enough to win GE15, and they would need more allies down the line,” Shazwan said.</p><p>He added that MIC, Gerakan, and even MCA may join PN, which would leave Umno out in the cold and the nationalist party would need to realign with other allies should this occur.</p><p>“Things are still fluid. While Bersatu and PAS have doubled down on their alliance in PN, Umno still held a high-level meeting with PAS using the Muafakat Nasional (MN) banner recently.</p><p>“Umno itself is currently at the crossroads as to which direction it should take. We can expect more clarity on this down the line as we head closer to the elections,” he told <em>Malay Mail</em>.</p><p><strong>‘Anyone’s call’</strong></p><p>Universiti Sains Malaysia’s (USM) political sociologist Prof Sivamurugan Pandian also agreed with Shazwan, adding that strategically, Bersatu and PAS can easily decide their seat allocations between themselves.</p><p>“BN might not face any seat allocation if it is going solo. Until GE15, it is difficult to say because we don’t know who will join who in the end. They will not face any issues in Malay-dominated seats. As with Bersatu and PAS, they may have to compromise on Malay seats.</p><p>“With Bersatu, PAS will have to sacrifice some traditional seats. But with other component members, they can continue to contest them. &nbsp;</p><p>“Next GE will be anyone’s call,” he said.</p><p>Last month, Bersatu and PAS confirmed that they will maintain their political cooperation through PN, well into GE15.</p><p>The decision, which was announced by the two parties’ secretaries-general, will leave nominal ally Umno on its own following the Malay nationalist party’s decision to reject Bersatu at its annual general assembly.</p><p>According to a statement by Bersatu secretary-general Datuk Seri Hamzah Zainuidin and his PAS counterpart Datuk Seri Takiyuddin Hassan, this was decided in a meeting involving the presidents of both parties.</p><p>They said their parties remained committed to reinforcing Muslim unification and were prepared to work with other parties that supported this vision.</p><p>The two leaders said their parties chose to remain with PN in the interests of political stability that was vital for the nation still grappling with the Covid-19 pandemic.</p><p>The statement appeared to mark a complete breakdown in the relationship between Bersatu and Umno, which the latter resolved to terminate going into the general election.</p><p>Prior to this, Bersatu had continued to extend the olive branch to Umno, while PAS tried to convince the Malay nationalists to return to PN in the interests of Muslim unity.</p><p><strong>Fight for same slice of pie</strong></p><p>Universiti Kebangsaan Malaysia political analyst Kartini Aboo Talib Khalid, when posed the question of how PN could move forward, envisioned possible conflict among Umno, Bersatu and PAS, since all three are vying for the same electorate.</p><p>She also concurred that the political partnership would be beneficial to Bersatu and PAS, but said that Bersatu may have to strive harder to win the trust of voters, especially since it has accepted many party hoppers.</p><p>“The alliance would allow both parties to work together in GE15. PAS would retain 18 or more seats. Bersatu may have to work harder to win voters’ trust because members were from Umno and PKR. Political hopping is not accepted by most voters, especially in urban areas, and hardcore members of the original party,” she told <em>Malay Mail</em>.</p><p>Kartini said that PAS already has seats set aside here, in Kelantan and Terengganu, as well as some parts of Kedah and Perak.</p><p>However, rather than the Opposition, Kartini painted a grim future for Umno, if it still proceeds under the leadership of its current president, Datuk Seri Ahmad Zahid Hamidi.</p><p>“Umno must conduct an internal election to select new members if it wants to stay relevant in GE15.</p><p>“The continuous effort by Zahid through Umno to work with PKR without DAP is already a bad sign for BN. DAP has most of the Chinese support in all urban areas and mixed seats. PKR may not want to break its alliance with DAP because urban voters may vote for PKR because of DAP,” she added.</p><p><strong>Two against one</strong></p><p>Geostrategist Prof Azmi Hassan, however, said that whatever the configuration — either PAS-Bersatu vs Umno or PAS-Umno vs Bersatu — all three parties stand to lose.</p><p>He said that when Bersatu, PAS and Umno go against each other individually or in an alliance, PH always has the advantage, as the Malay votes that the three parties seek are now split in two.</p><p>“So as I see it, no matter what, two versus one will never work with these three entities. They need to cooperate, they need to agree, especially on seat allocation, so that it is three versus one.</p><p>“Three meaning Bersatu, PAS and Umno versus PH. In that case, it will be detrimental to PH, as the three Malay-based parties will gain leeway or a huge advantage in terms of support from Malay voters,” Azmi said.</p><p>He also predicted that PAS will dump Bersatu for Umno as GE15 draws closer, as Umno still has a strong foothold in the Malay heartland.</p><p>“As to the viability of the partnership with Bersatu, PAS, in this case, once GE15 is near, will realise that it is better to be with Umno, because Umno has a strong presence in the Malay heartland, especially Kelantan, Terengganu and Kedah.</p><p>“So in this case, PAS vs Umno is not good. On the other hand, if it is PAS vs Bersatu, the latter has yet to prove it is a formidable force in the Malay heartland.</p><p>“It is for this reason that PAS might abandon the PN ship and join hands with Umno for GE15, but it all depends on PAS and Umno leadership to make it happen,” Azmi added.</p><p><br />&nbsp;</p>
            ]]></content:encoded>
                        <dc:creator>Yiswaree Palansamy</dc:creator>
                        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 06:00:18 +0800</pubDate>
            <dc:subject>umno,pas,parti pribumi bersatu malaysia,perikatan nasional,umno</dc:subject>
        </item>
                <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PM says govt to continue empowering roles of Social Welfare Dept]]></title>
            <link>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/11/pm-says-govt-to-continue-empowering-roles-of-social-welfare-dept/1965720</link>
            <guid>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/11/pm-says-govt-to-continue-empowering-roles-of-social-welfare-dept/1965720</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[PUTRAJAYA, April 11 — Prime Minister Tan Sri Muhyiddin Yassin said the roles of the Social Welfare Department (JKM) as well as its employees would continue to be empowered through the implementation of several initiatives to ensure the delivery of...]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
                                <p><figure class="figure  float-left" style="width:800px">
        <img src="https://media2.malaymail.com/uploads/articles/2021/2021-02/FW1143939_PTJ11_16022021_PANDUAN_BN202102159237-lpr.jpg" class="figure-img img-fluid rounded" alt="Prime Minister Tan Sri Muhyiddin Yassin delivers a speech at the launch of the National Covid-19 Immunisation Programme Handbook at the Perdana Putra Building in Putrajaya February 16, 2021. — Bernama pic" title="Prime Minister Tan Sri Muhyiddin Yassin delivers a speech at the launch of the National Covid-19 Immunisation Programme Handbook at the Perdana Putra Building in Putrajaya February 16, 2021. — Bernama pic" width='800'  height='533'>
        <figcaption class="figure-caption">Prime Minister Tan Sri Muhyiddin Yassin delivers a speech at the launch of the National Covid-19 Immunisation Programme Handbook at the Perdana Putra Building in Putrajaya February 16, 2021. — Bernama pic</figcaption>
    </figure>
    <div class="clearfix"></div>
    <div>
        <p class="font-italic">Subscribe to our <a class="font-weight-bold" href="https://t.me/themalaymail" target="_blank">Telegram</a> channel for the latest updates on news you need to know.</p>
        <hr/>
    </div><p>PUTRAJAYA, April 11 — Prime Minister Tan Sri Muhyiddin Yassin said the roles of the Social Welfare Department (JKM) as well as its employees would continue to be empowered through the implementation of several initiatives to ensure the delivery of efficient and people-friendly welfare assistance services.</p><p>Among the initiatives included the restructuring of JKM which cover efforts to enhance the delivery of aid, streamlining of posts as well as improving the distribution of duties apart from granting special allowances to JKM staff who serve at risk areas such as senior citizen and people with disabilities (OKU) institutions, he said.</p><p>Other initiatives included formulating the Social Work Profession Bill to ensure the welfare of social workers is protected including Community Welfare Officers so that they are recognised according to their respective expertise.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>Speaking at the Appreciation Night and 75th anniversary of the Social Welfare Department here tonight, Muhyiddin said JKM was among the core pillars which forged the direction of social development in the country.</p><p>“JKM staff have shown dedicated commitment in taking on their responsibilities to look after all sections of community,” he said.</p><p>Muhyiddin said when the nation was facing the Covid-19 pandemic, JKM played an important role especially in ensuring the success of humanitarian and social welfare missions to help in the government’s efforts to curb the infection despite facing various constraints.</p><p>This included the distribution of food baskets during the implementation of movement control order (MCO) apart from JKM being involved in managing the various aspects of welfare at Covid-19 quarantine centres throughout the country.</p><p>As an additional initiative to assist and assured the people affected by Covid-19, the Ministry of Women, Family and Community Development (KPWKM) was also actively carrying out the Malaysia Prihatin Programme since November last year.</p><p>Through the programme, he said various forms of assistance were rendered including daily necessities and social support for the grassroots to lighten the burden of the people.</p><p>He said the assistance channelled through the Prihatin events is the result of the support and contributions of the corporate sector, non-governmental organisations and local community.</p><p>At the ceremony, Muhyiddin also presented the National Jacket Hero Icon award to two JKM officers, namely Tuah Sajali and Dayang Rugayah Awang Besar for their services and contributions, especially during the Covid-19 pandemic.</p><p>Also present at the ceremony were Women, Family and Community Development Minister Datuk Seri Rina Mohd Harun and her deputy Datuk Siti Zailah Mohd Yusoff. — Bernama</p>
            ]]></content:encoded>
                        <dc:creator></dc:creator>
                        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 23:54:51 +0800</pubDate>
            <dc:subject>muhyiddin yassin,social welfare department</dc:subject>
        </item>
                <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Domestic Trade Ministry will ensure Malaysia’s business community’s concerns reflected in govt decisions]]></title>
            <link>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/11/domestic-trade-ministry-will-ensure-malaysias-business-communitys-concerns/1965719</link>
            <guid>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/11/domestic-trade-ministry-will-ensure-malaysias-business-communitys-concerns/1965719</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[KLANG, April 11 — Ministry of Domestic Trade and Consumer Affairs (MDTCA) will ensure that the concerns of the business community are reflected in the decisions that the government has made, and will make in formulating decisions. Its minister,...]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
                                <p><figure class="figure  float-left" style="width:800px">
        <img src="https://media2.malaymail.com/uploads/articles/2021/2021-01/alexander_nanta_linggi_06012021.jpg" class="figure-img img-fluid rounded" alt="Domestic Trade and Consumer Affairs Minister Datuk Seri Alexander Nanta Linggi speaks at a press conference in Putrajaya, December 18, 2020. — Bernama pic" title="Domestic Trade and Consumer Affairs Minister Datuk Seri Alexander Nanta Linggi speaks at a press conference in Putrajaya, December 18, 2020. — Bernama pic" width='800'  height='533'>
        <figcaption class="figure-caption">Domestic Trade and Consumer Affairs Minister Datuk Seri Alexander Nanta Linggi speaks at a press conference in Putrajaya, December 18, 2020. — Bernama pic</figcaption>
    </figure>
    <div class="clearfix"></div>
    <div>
        <p class="font-italic">Subscribe to our <a class="font-weight-bold" href="https://t.me/themalaymail" target="_blank">Telegram</a> channel for the latest updates on news you need to know.</p>
        <hr/>
    </div><p>KLANG, April 11 — Ministry of Domestic Trade and Consumer Affairs (MDTCA) will ensure that the concerns of the business community are reflected in the decisions that the government has made, and will make in formulating decisions.</p><p>Its minister, Datuk Seri Alexander Nanta Linggi said he appreciates how the government was willing to listen to the concerns raised by the business community, especially with regard to the reopening of the economy.</p><p>“I personally am also grateful to the business community for playing a very active role in cooperating with MDTCA in forming a committee to advise the government in formulating standard operating procedures (SOPs) for the retail sector and for constantly allocating the resources and manpower to ensure these SOPs are adhered to.</p><p>“The government would not have been able to pull through without the help of the business community, and for that, thank you,” he said in his speech at the Lang International Corporate Titan Awards (LICTA) here today.</p><p>He said MDTCA welcomed recommendations and constructive criticisms from the business community with regard to any concerns they faced due to the impact of Covid-19, or any other matter relating to domestic trade.</p><p>“MDTCA is aware that there is a need to find the right balance in addressing concerns of the people’s wellbeing as well as businesses, and that if this issue is not managed well, we might find ourselves in the midst of and in an economic breakdown with people losing their jobs and companies having to foreclose,” he said.</p><p>Nanta said MDTCA is very aware of its important role in facilitating domestic trade, from retail, the franchise sector, business development, business registration, copyright to competition. — Bernama</p>
            ]]></content:encoded>
                        <dc:creator></dc:creator>
                        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 23:48:02 +0800</pubDate>
            <dc:subject>domestic trade and consumer affairs ministry</dc:subject>
        </item>
                <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PM says mulling proposal to set up centralised database to coordinate review of aid recipients’ eligibility, records]]></title>
            <link>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/11/pm-says-mulling-proposal-to-set-up-centralised-database-to-coordinate-revie/1965713</link>
            <guid>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/11/pm-says-mulling-proposal-to-set-up-centralised-database-to-coordinate-revie/1965713</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[PUTRAJAYA, April 11 — A proposal has been made to set up a centralised database to coordinate the review on the eligibility and records of aid recipients, said Prime Minister Tan Sri Muhyiddin Yassin. He said the proposal was among the new...]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
                                <p><figure class="figure  float-left" style="width:800px">
        <img src="https://media2.malaymail.com/uploads/articles/2021/2021-02/20210228_muhyiddinBernamaLead.jpg" class="figure-img img-fluid rounded" alt="Prime Minister Tan Sri Muhyiddin Yassin during a special interview with several media organisations on his first year in office at his residence in Bukit Damansara, February 28,2021. — Bernama pic" title="Prime Minister Tan Sri Muhyiddin Yassin during a special interview with several media organisations on his first year in office at his residence in Bukit Damansara, February 28,2021. — Bernama pic" width='800'  height='542'>
        <figcaption class="figure-caption">Prime Minister Tan Sri Muhyiddin Yassin during a special interview with several media organisations on his first year in office at his residence in Bukit Damansara, February 28,2021. — Bernama pic</figcaption>
    </figure>
    <div class="clearfix"></div>
    <div>
        <p class="font-italic">Subscribe to our <a class="font-weight-bold" href="https://t.me/themalaymail" target="_blank">Telegram</a> channel for the latest updates on news you need to know.</p>
        <hr/>
    </div><p>PUTRAJAYA, April 11 — A proposal has been made to set up a centralised database to coordinate the review on the eligibility and records of aid recipients, said Prime Minister Tan Sri Muhyiddin Yassin.</p><p>He said the proposal was among the new direction for the distribution of social aid, which was discussed at a National Economic Action Council meeting that he chaired on February 22.</p><p>Speaking at the appreciation ceremony in conjunction with the 75th anniversary of the Social Welfare Department (JKM) here today, Muhyiddin said the database was necessary as there were 192 types of assistance being channelled to the people across various government agencies.</p><p>“Anyone who meets the eligibility criteria must be treated fairly and equitably. This fulfils the principle of caring that is the core approach of the Perikatan Nasional government today,” he said.</p><p>He also wants all agencies involved in providing social aid to coordinate the delivery mechanism so that assistance could be provided to those in need immediately.</p><p>Muhyiddin said JKM staff needed to become proactive and efficient agents of delivery among the communities.</p><p>“For example, whenever the government makes an announcement, especially regarding welfare aid, you must act fast to ensure efforts to present the message and aid to the society in the respective communities are done correctly and effectively.</p><p>“This includes improving the aid application process, reducing bureaucratic constraints and ensuring assistance actually reaches those in need, regardless of religion, race and background,” he said.</p><p>The Prime Minister said he was aware that many people, especially among the JKM aid recipients, were badly affected by the Covid-19 pandemic.</p><p>As such, he said, the government had taken a proactive and holistic approach since the start by introducing various economic stimulus packages such as the Prihatin Rakyat Economic Stimulus Package (Prihatin), National Economic Recovery Plan (Penjana), Kita Prihatin, Malaysian Economic and Rakyat’s Protection Assistance Package (Permai) and the latest one, Strategic Programme to Empower People and the Economy (Pemerkasa).</p><p>Muhyiddin said these initiatives were crucial to ensuring that all assistance could be channelled to the targeted groups to help the people under the national economic recovery phase. — Bernama</p>
            ]]></content:encoded>
                        <dc:creator></dc:creator>
                        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 23:20:42 +0800</pubDate>
            <dc:subject>muhyiddin yassin,database,national economic action council,aid recipients</dc:subject>
        </item>
                <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Covid-19: Sarawak will consider scrapping 14-day quarantine if situation improves, says DCM]]></title>
            <link>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/11/covid-19-sarawak-will-consider-scrapping-14-day-quarantine-if-situation-imp/1965712</link>
            <guid>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/11/covid-19-sarawak-will-consider-scrapping-14-day-quarantine-if-situation-imp/1965712</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[KUCHING, April 11 — The Sarawak government will consider the suggested scrapping of the 14-day compulsory quarantine for entry into the state if the Covid-19 situation in Malaysia improves, says Deputy Chief Minister, Datuk Amar Douglas Uggah...]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
                                <p><figure class="figure  float-left" style="width:800px">
        <img src="https://media2.malaymail.com/uploads/articles/2020/2020-08/douglas_uggah_ukas_1808.jpg" class="figure-img img-fluid rounded" alt="Sarawak Disaster Management Committee chairman Datuk Douglas Uggah speaks to reporters at a press conference August 18, 2020. ― Picture courtesy of the Sarawak Public Communications Unit" title="Sarawak Disaster Management Committee chairman Datuk Douglas Uggah speaks to reporters at a press conference August 18, 2020. ― Picture courtesy of the Sarawak Public Communications Unit" width='800'  height='546'>
        <figcaption class="figure-caption">Sarawak Disaster Management Committee chairman Datuk Douglas Uggah speaks to reporters at a press conference August 18, 2020. ― Picture courtesy of the Sarawak Public Communications Unit</figcaption>
    </figure>
    <div class="clearfix"></div>
    <div>
        <p class="font-italic">Subscribe to our <a class="font-weight-bold" href="https://t.me/themalaymail" target="_blank">Telegram</a> channel for the latest updates on news you need to know.</p>
        <hr/>
    </div><p>KUCHING, April 11 — The Sarawak government will consider the suggested scrapping of the 14-day compulsory quarantine for entry into the state if the Covid-19 situation in Malaysia improves, says Deputy Chief Minister, Datuk Amar Douglas Uggah Embas.</p><p>Uggah who is also the State Disaster Management Committee (JPBN) chairman, said the number of Covid-19 positive cases was increasing in Sarawak, hence if quarantine were to be terminated, it could worsen the situation.</p><p>He said that besides facing the problem of daily transmissions, the entry of illegal immigrants via the Sarawak-Indonesia border was also threatening the current situation in the state as it also contributed to the high number of Covid-19 infections.</p><p>“We understand and sympathise (with those family members facing difficulty to return due to the quarantine order) but in the current scenario, we want Sarawakians to also understand the situation.</p><p>“In fact, this standard operating procedure is necessary to protect Sarawak, not to discriminate or to stop family members from meeting. This is a very difficult situation, but there will be a time when we feel that it’s no longer necessary...we will lift it,” he told reporters at the JPBN’s daily news conference, here, today.</p><p>Earlier, a petition has been made for the Sarawak state government to scrap the 14-day compulsory quarantine as it is seen as burdensome.</p><p>The petition also states that most Sarawakians, whether working in the government or private sector, have not been able to return to their families for a long time since the Covid-19 pandemic hit the country.</p><p>Today, Sarawak once again recorded a high number of Covid-19 positive cases with 443, bringing the cumulative number in the state to 20,001 cases.</p><p>The Sarawak State Health Department also announced three more new clusters, namely the Abak Bon Cluster in Subis, Jalan Badarudin Cluster in Kuching and Nanga Kelangas Cluster in Julau. — Bernama</p>
            ]]></content:encoded>
                        <dc:creator></dc:creator>
                        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 22:59:46 +0800</pubDate>
            <dc:subject>douglas uggah embas,covid-19,covid-19 quarantine,sarawak disaster management committee sdmc</dc:subject>
        </item>
                <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Selangor exco: Proposal to degazette Kuala Langat North Forest Reserve still under discussion]]></title>
            <link>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/11/selangor-exco-proposal-to-degazette-kuala-langat-north-forest-reserve-still/1965706</link>
            <guid>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/11/selangor-exco-proposal-to-degazette-kuala-langat-north-forest-reserve-still/1965706</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[BESTARI JAYA, April 11 — The proposal to degazette the Kuala Langat North Forest Reserve is still under discussion and the Selangor government is examining the views of relevant experts, said Selangor Tourism, Environment, Green Technology and...]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
                                <p><figure class="figure  float-left" style="width:800px">
        <img src="https://media2.malaymail.com/uploads/articles/2020/2020-11/Hee_Loy_Sian_indah_water_1011_(2).jpg" class="figure-img img-fluid rounded" alt="Selangor executive councillor Hee said many aspects need to be taken into account before a decision on the status of the degazetting of the forest is made including the socio-economy, development and welfare of the Orang Asli. — Picture by Firdaus Latif" title="Selangor executive councillor Hee said many aspects need to be taken into account before a decision on the status of the degazetting of the forest is made including the socio-economy, development and welfare of the Orang Asli. — Picture by Firdaus Latif" width='800'  height='534'>
        <figcaption class="figure-caption">Selangor executive councillor Hee said many aspects need to be taken into account before a decision on the status of the degazetting of the forest is made including the socio-economy, development and welfare of the Orang Asli. — Picture by Firdaus Latif</figcaption>
    </figure>
    <div class="clearfix"></div>
    <div>
        <p class="font-italic">Subscribe to our <a class="font-weight-bold" href="https://t.me/themalaymail" target="_blank">Telegram</a> channel for the latest updates on news you need to know.</p>
        <hr/>
    </div><p>BESTARI JAYA, April 11 — The proposal to degazette the Kuala Langat North Forest Reserve is still under discussion and the Selangor government is examining the views of relevant experts, said Selangor Tourism, Environment, Green Technology and Orang Asli Affairs Committee chairman Hee Loy Sian.</p><p>Hee said many aspects need to be taken into account before a decision on the status of the degazetting of the forest is made including the socio-economy, development and welfare of the Orang Asli.</p><p>“I am also taking into account the views of experts and professors from Universiti Putra Malaysia, Universiti Kebangsaan Malaysia, and other universities on whether the forest should be degazetted or not.</p><p>“We respect the views of non-governmental organisations and the Orang Asli, and as a caring government, we will look at all aspects not only of forests but the Orang Asli, and economic and development aspects,” he told reporters after handing over a land title to a Chinese temple here, today.</p><p>He said if the degazetting of the Kuala Langat North Forest Reserve is implemented, the state government would replace it with better forests.</p><p>“We will not reduce the number of forest reserves in the state of Selangor. That is why we have to think about many aspects because if we want to remove it, we have to find a replacement (forest) that is of better quality than the existing one...that is our policy.</p><p>“So to have development in the state of Selangor we will ensure that the total forest area is maintained at or more than 32 per cent,” he said.</p><p>The Kuala Langat North Forest Reserve, gazetted on May 13, 1927, and located in Mukim Tanjung 12, Kuala Langat district in Selangor, came to public attention following notice of public investigation under Section 11 of the National Forestry (Adoption) Enactment 1985 (Subrule 7 (2)) by the Selangor Forestry Department early last year.</p><p>The notice, which seeks to gain public opinion following the proposed degazetting of the forest reserve, sparked controversy among the community, especially the Orang Asli community who have depended on the forest for their livelihood for hundreds of years. — Bernama</p>
            ]]></content:encoded>
                        <dc:creator></dc:creator>
                        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 22:34:01 +0800</pubDate>
            <dc:subject>hee loy sian,kuala langat north forest reserve</dc:subject>
        </item>
                <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pejuang yet to decide on joining any coalition, says Mukhriz]]></title>
            <link>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/11/pejuang-yet-to-decide-on-joining-any-coalition-says-mukhriz/1965705</link>
            <guid>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/11/pejuang-yet-to-decide-on-joining-any-coalition-says-mukhriz/1965705</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[KOTA BARU, April 11 — Parti Pejuang Tanah Air (Pejuang) has yet to decide on whether to fight its own battle or join any political coalition, said its president Datuk Seri Mukhriz Mahathir. He said Pejuang was still open in the matter and would...]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
                                <p><figure class="figure  float-left" style="width:800px">
        <img src="https://media2.malaymail.com/uploads/articles/2020/2020-01/mukhriz_mahathir_sunway_1301_(1).jpg" class="figure-img img-fluid rounded" alt="Datuk Seri Mukhriz Mahathir said Pejuang has yet to decide on whether to fight its own battle or join any political coalition. — Picture by Choo Choy May" title="Datuk Seri Mukhriz Mahathir said Pejuang has yet to decide on whether to fight its own battle or join any political coalition. — Picture by Choo Choy May" width='800'  height='534'>
        <figcaption class="figure-caption">Datuk Seri Mukhriz Mahathir said Pejuang has yet to decide on whether to fight its own battle or join any political coalition. — Picture by Choo Choy May</figcaption>
    </figure>
    <div class="clearfix"></div>
    <div>
        <p class="font-italic">Subscribe to our <a class="font-weight-bold" href="https://t.me/themalaymail" target="_blank">Telegram</a> channel for the latest updates on news you need to know.</p>
        <hr/>
    </div><p>KOTA BARU, April 11 — Parti Pejuang Tanah Air (Pejuang) has yet to decide on whether to fight its own battle or join any political coalition, said its president Datuk Seri Mukhriz Mahathir.</p><p>He said Pejuang was still open in the matter and would make the announcement when the time comes.</p><p>“We know that we have to fight based on our own abilities. We also know our strengths and weaknesses. So, we will be careful in terms of the number of seats to contest (in the election) and is it necessary to cooperate with any party.</p><p>“Maybe we will join a coalition or make an electoral pact for the election,” he told reporters after launching the Kelantan branch of the party here, today.</p><p>Mukhriz said, for the time being, Pejuang was still in the third bloc, namely not cooperating with any political party.</p><p>“We have our own stance and it seems like the stance is right,” he said.</p><p>When asked about the total number of Pejuang members, Mukhriz said since the party has yet to be officially registered, the membership count has not been made in full but claimed that tens of thousands have registered as Pejuang members online. — Bernama</p>
            ]]></content:encoded>
                        <dc:creator></dc:creator>
                        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 21:47:37 +0800</pubDate>
            <dc:subject>mukhriz mahathir,pejuang</dc:subject>
        </item>
                <item>
            <title><![CDATA[As daily cases rise, Sarawak Pakatan urges state to buy its own Covid-19 vax]]></title>
            <link>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/11/as-daily-cases-rise-sarawak-pakatan-urges-state-to-buy-its-own-covid-19-vax/1965698</link>
            <guid>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/11/as-daily-cases-rise-sarawak-pakatan-urges-state-to-buy-its-own-covid-19-vax/1965698</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[KUCHING, April 11 — Sarawak Pakatan Harapan (PH) wants the state government to purchase its own Covid-19 vaccines instead of relying on the federal government in view of the state’s daily high cases. Its chairman Chong Chieng Jen pointed out...]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
                                <p><figure class="figure  float-left" style="width:800px">
        <img src="https://media2.malaymail.com/uploads/articles/2021/2021-03/20210302HR6_malaysia_covid-19_vaccination_uitm.JPG" class="figure-img img-fluid rounded" alt="A healthcare worker administers a dose of the Pfizer-BioNTech Covid-19 vaccine to a frontliner at the UiTM Private Specialist Centre in Sungai Buloh March 2, 2021. ― Picture by Hari Anggara" title="A healthcare worker administers a dose of the Pfizer-BioNTech Covid-19 vaccine to a frontliner at the UiTM Private Specialist Centre in Sungai Buloh March 2, 2021. ― Picture by Hari Anggara" width='800'  height='534'>
        <figcaption class="figure-caption">A healthcare worker administers a dose of the Pfizer-BioNTech Covid-19 vaccine to a frontliner at the UiTM Private Specialist Centre in Sungai Buloh March 2, 2021. ― Picture by Hari Anggara</figcaption>
    </figure>
    <div class="clearfix"></div>
    <div>
        <p class="font-italic">Subscribe to our <a class="font-weight-bold" href="https://t.me/themalaymail" target="_blank">Telegram</a> channel for the latest updates on news you need to know.</p>
        <hr/>
    </div><p>KUCHING, April 11 — Sarawak Pakatan Harapan (PH) wants the state government to purchase its own Covid-19 vaccines instead of relying on the federal government in view of the state’s daily high cases.</p><p>Its chairman Chong Chieng Jen pointed out that Sarawak ranked among the country’s top three out of 16 states and territories in the past one month, adding that there seems to be no sign of an improvement in the weeks ahead.</p><p>“This is despite the more stringent standard operating procedures (SOP) on quarantine, movement control and border control measures imposed by the Sarawak Disaster Management Committee (SDMC) than those imposed by the federal Ministry of Health (MOH) in terms of the pandemic management.</p><p>“While the so-called more relaxed SOP-states are now registering a decline in new infection cases, the more stringent SOP-Sarawak is having higher new infection cases,” he said in a statement today.</p><p>Chong urged Chief Minister Datuk Abang Johari Openg to “walk the talk” to purchase the vaccine for all Sarawakians, saying senior state officials have been saying so since February.</p><p>“This is the most welcomed announcement for all. But, almost two months have passed and yet the state government is still talking about asking for more vaccine quota from the federal government,” the Sarawak DAP chairman said.</p><p>He said that the sooner the vaccination programme rolls out, the sooner Sarawak can fully resume its economic activities.</p><p>He added that the DAP is willing to help the state government register Sarawakians for the vaccination programme.</p><img  alt=""  height="693"  src="https://media2.malaymail.com/uploads/articles/2021/2021-04/COVID19_Current_status_Malaysia_Apr11-2021.jpg"  style="width:800px"  width="800"  title=""  caption=""  class=" float-left"  ><p></p>
            ]]></content:encoded>
                        <dc:creator>Sulok Tawie</dc:creator>
                        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 21:17:07 +0800</pubDate>
            <dc:subject>sarawak state government,chong chieng jen,covid-19,covid-19 vaccination</dc:subject>
        </item>
                <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Police expose 19 distributors involved in imported meat cartel activities across six states]]></title>
            <link>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/11/police-expose-19-distributors-involved-in-imported-meat-cartel-activities-a/1965697</link>
            <guid>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/11/police-expose-19-distributors-involved-in-imported-meat-cartel-activities-a/1965697</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[JOHOR BARU, April 11 — A total of 19 cold distribution companies were found to be involved in imported meat cartel activities in an operation conducted in six states simultaneously two days ago (April 9). Bukit Aman Criminal Investigation...]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
                                <p><figure class="figure  float-left" style="width:800px">
        <img src="https://media2.malaymail.com/uploads/articles/2021/2021-03/Huzir_Mohamed_31032021.jpg" class="figure-img img-fluid rounded" alt="Bukit Aman Criminal Investigation Department (CID) director Datuk Huzir Mohamed speaks to the media after officiating the Nilai district police headquarters, March 31, 2021. — Bernama pic" title="Bukit Aman Criminal Investigation Department (CID) director Datuk Huzir Mohamed speaks to the media after officiating the Nilai district police headquarters, March 31, 2021. — Bernama pic" width='800'  height='533'>
        <figcaption class="figure-caption">Bukit Aman Criminal Investigation Department (CID) director Datuk Huzir Mohamed speaks to the media after officiating the Nilai district police headquarters, March 31, 2021. — Bernama pic</figcaption>
    </figure>
    <div class="clearfix"></div>
    <div>
        <p class="font-italic">Subscribe to our <a class="font-weight-bold" href="https://t.me/themalaymail" target="_blank">Telegram</a> channel for the latest updates on news you need to know.</p>
        <hr/>
    </div><p>JOHOR BARU, April 11 — A total of 19 cold distribution companies were found to be involved in imported meat cartel activities in an operation conducted in six states simultaneously two days ago (April 9).</p><p>Bukit Aman Criminal Investigation Department (CID) director Datuk Huzir Mohamed said seven of the companies were in Johor, Federal Territory of Kuala Lumpur (four), Selangor (four), Perak (one), Penang (two) and Kedah (one).</p><p>He said the 19 companies were found to have conspired with a local company that was allowed to import frozen meat from Brazil legally.</p><p>“According to the importer’s permit, the company could only import 27 tons of meat for one permit issued. Investigations revealed that the company only used four of five importer’s permits issued for 2020.</p><p>“The importer, however, was found to have distributed more than 1,000 tonnes to 202 customers as proven by seized invoices. Investigations also revealed the annual profit of the 19 companies were between RM1 million to RM52 million,” he told reporters at the Johor contingent police headquarters here today.</p><p>During Op Kartel Daging, CID also arrested 36 individuals, 26 men and 10 women, aged between 28 and 67. Thirty-four of them were company directors and two were company managers.</p><p>Besides importing from Brazil, the importer also received supplies from local companies, which would be repackaged before distribution to customers.</p><p>He said the company also prepared boxes with halal logo to repackage the meat to fulfill customer orders.</p><p>“We found that the company received many orders because it offered lower prices compared to other halal meat distributors, as well as three-month credit facilities compared to ‘Cash on Delivery’ practised by other companies,” he said, adding that these activities had caused concern and doubts over the halal status of meat in the market.</p><p>Huzir said this not only impacted Muslims but also all Malaysians as the cleanliness of the repackaged meat could not be determined and it had not been approved by the veterinary department.</p><p>He said the police would continue their investigations into the issue and expected more arrests to follow, adding that they were tracking down two men believed to be the masterminds behind the cartel.</p><p>On Dec 1 last year, a raid conducted by several enforcement agencies on a frozen warehouse in Senai near here exposed the activities of a cartel that was smuggling in meat from overseas and repackaging it with halal logos for sale throughout Malaysia. — Bernama</p>
            ]]></content:encoded>
                        <dc:creator></dc:creator>
                        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 21:04:51 +0800</pubDate>
            <dc:subject>pdrm,bukit aman,meat cartel scandal,halal meat cartel</dc:subject>
        </item>
                <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EMCO in eight localities in Tawau from Monday, says Ismail Sabri]]></title>
            <link>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/11/emco-in-eight-localities-in-tawau-from-monday-says-ismail-sabri/1965696</link>
            <guid>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/11/emco-in-eight-localities-in-tawau-from-monday-says-ismail-sabri/1965696</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[KUALA LUMPUR, April 11 — Eight localities in Tawau, Sabah will come under the enhanced movement control order (EMCO) starting tomorrow until April 25 following the spread of Covid-19 with high infectivity rates. Senior Minister (Security Cluster)...]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
                                <p><figure class="figure  float-left" style="width:800px">
        <img src="https://media2.malaymail.com/uploads/articles/2021/2021-01/ismail_sabri_220121.jpg" class="figure-img img-fluid rounded" alt="Senior Minister (Security Cluster) Datuk Seri Ismail Sabri Yaakob said eight localities in Tawau, Sabah will come under EMCO starting tomorrow until April 25. ― Bernama pic" title="Senior Minister (Security Cluster) Datuk Seri Ismail Sabri Yaakob said eight localities in Tawau, Sabah will come under EMCO starting tomorrow until April 25. ― Bernama pic" width='800'  height='533'>
        <figcaption class="figure-caption">Senior Minister (Security Cluster) Datuk Seri Ismail Sabri Yaakob said eight localities in Tawau, Sabah will come under EMCO starting tomorrow until April 25. ― Bernama pic</figcaption>
    </figure>
    <div class="clearfix"></div>
    <div>
        <p class="font-italic">Subscribe to our <a class="font-weight-bold" href="https://t.me/themalaymail" target="_blank">Telegram</a> channel for the latest updates on news you need to know.</p>
        <hr/>
    </div><p>KUALA LUMPUR, April 11 — Eight localities in Tawau, Sabah will come under the enhanced movement control order (EMCO) starting tomorrow until April 25 following the spread of Covid-19 with high infectivity rates.</p><p>Senior Minister (Security Cluster) Datuk Seri Ismail Sabri Yaakob said the localities involved were Taman Sri Bukit Tawau, Taman Cahaya, Jalan Tengku Osman, Tawau Fire and Rescue Department staff quarters, Bandar Sri Indah, Jalan Mesra, Kampung Titingan and Taman Golden Hill.</p><p>He said cumulatively, 76 Covid-19 cases and 220 close contacts have been traced in the localities to date.</p><p>“The implementation of the EMCO is to control residents’ movement so as to curb the coronavirus transmission to outside communities,” he said in a statement on the development of Conditional MCO and Recovery MCO today.</p><p>Meanwhile, Ismail Sabri said a total of 208 individuals were arrested for flouting the standard operating procedures yesterday, of which 199 individuals were compounded while nine others remanded.</p><p>He said entertainment centre activities were the highest recorded offences involving 112 people, followed by failure to provide equipment to record customers’ details (27), not wearing face masks (16) and others (53).</p><p>Through Op Benteng yesterday, Ismail Sabri said nine illegal immigrants were detained, seven were deported and three land vehicles were seized.</p><p>A total of 256 roadblocks were also mounted nationwide yesterday.</p><p>Over the past 24 hours, he said 807 individuals arrived at the country’s international entry points and have been sent to undergo quarantine at quarantine stations across the country.</p><p>Cumulatively, 170,888 individuals have returned from abroad since July 24, 2020, and placed in 79 hotels and eight public training institutes and private higher learning institutions across the country.</p><p>“Of the total, 7,868 individuals are undergoing quarantine, 161,681 allowed to return home and 1,339 sent to hospitals,” he said. — Bernama</p>
            ]]></content:encoded>
                        <dc:creator></dc:creator>
                        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 20:53:48 +0800</pubDate>
            <dc:subject>ismail sabri yaakob,tawau,covid-19,enhanced movement control order emco</dc:subject>
        </item>
                <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Johor BN begins discussions on seat distribution for GE15, says chairman]]></title>
            <link>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/11/johor-bn-begins-discussions-on-seat-distribution-for-ge15-says-chairman/1965694</link>
            <guid>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/11/johor-bn-begins-discussions-on-seat-distribution-for-ge15-says-chairman/1965694</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[JOHOR BARU, April 11 — Johor Barisan Nasional (BN) has begun discussions on the distribution of seats to contest in the upcoming 15th General Election (GE15) between its component parties, said Johor BN chairman Datuk Hasni Mohammad. Hasni said...]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
                                <p><figure class="figure  float-left" style="width:800px">
        <img src="https://media2.malaymail.com/uploads/articles/2020/2020-10/Hasni_Mohammad_28102020.jpeg" class="figure-img img-fluid rounded" alt="Datuk Hasni Mohammad said Johor BN has begun discussions on the distribution of seats to contest in the upcoming GE15 between its component parties. — Picture by Ben Tan" title="Datuk Hasni Mohammad said Johor BN has begun discussions on the distribution of seats to contest in the upcoming GE15 between its component parties. — Picture by Ben Tan" width='800'  height='599'>
        <figcaption class="figure-caption">Datuk Hasni Mohammad said Johor BN has begun discussions on the distribution of seats to contest in the upcoming GE15 between its component parties. — Picture by Ben Tan</figcaption>
    </figure>
    <div class="clearfix"></div>
    <div>
        <p class="font-italic">Subscribe to our <a class="font-weight-bold" href="https://t.me/themalaymail" target="_blank">Telegram</a> channel for the latest updates on news you need to know.</p>
        <hr/>
    </div><p>JOHOR BARU, April 11 — Johor Barisan Nasional (BN) has begun discussions on the distribution of seats to contest in the upcoming 15th General Election (GE15) between its component parties, said Johor BN chairman Datuk Hasni Mohammad.</p><p>Hasni said Johor BN had decided that Umno, MCA and MIC would contest in the election.</p><p>“I have started the discussions with the leaders of component parties in BN, namely MCA and MIC. We understand the concept (cooperation). We (BN Johor) agree that MCA and MIC need to contest,” he told reporters after closing the ‘Bangkit 15’ programme hosted by Umno Training and Cadre Bureau, here today.</p><p>Hasni, who is also Johor UMNO Liaison Committee chairman said, however, the discussions had yet to finalise the constituencies and the number of seats for each component, adding that the discussions so far only involved Johor BN component parties.</p><p>Meanwhile, on the ‘Bangkit 15’ programme, the Johor Menteri Besar said it was an effort to strengthen the Johor UMNO machinery apart from improving methods and training in facing the GE15.</p><p>“We have discussed several things (during the ‘Bangkit 15’ programme) such as the campaign approach, methods to adopt during the election. We want MCA and MIC to also use the same methods as practised by Johor UMNO,” he added. — Bernama</p>
            ]]></content:encoded>
                        <dc:creator></dc:creator>
                        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 20:48:35 +0800</pubDate>
            <dc:subject>mca,umno,mic,barisan nasional,hasni mohammad,johor bn,umno</dc:subject>
        </item>
                <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MOF dismisses claims MSSB sold shares, says still major shareholder involved in Exchange 106 in TRX]]></title>
            <link>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/11/mof-dismisses-claims-mssb-sold-shares-says-still-major-shareholder-involved/1965693</link>
            <guid>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/11/mof-dismisses-claims-mssb-sold-shares-says-still-major-shareholder-involved/1965693</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[KUALA LUMPUR, April 11 — The Ministry of Finance (MoF) today clarified that MKD Signature Sdn Bhd (MSSB), a company owned by Minister of Finance (Incorporated) [MoF (Inc)] is still the major shareholder of Mulia Property Development Sdn Bhd...]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
                                <p><figure class="figure  float-left" style="width:800px">
        <img src="https://media2.malaymail.com/uploads/articles/2015-07/1mdb_trx_construction_20150703.JPG" class="figure-img img-fluid rounded" alt="A man looks out at the 1Malaysia Development Berhad (1MDB) flagship Tun Razak Exchange development in Kuala Lumpur, July 3, 2015. — Reuters pic" title="A man looks out at the 1Malaysia Development Berhad (1MDB) flagship Tun Razak Exchange development in Kuala Lumpur, July 3, 2015. — Reuters pic" width='800'  height='520'>
        <figcaption class="figure-caption">A man looks out at the 1Malaysia Development Berhad (1MDB) flagship Tun Razak Exchange development in Kuala Lumpur, July 3, 2015. — Reuters pic</figcaption>
    </figure>
    <div class="clearfix"></div>
    <div>
        <p class="font-italic">Subscribe to our <a class="font-weight-bold" href="https://t.me/themalaymail" target="_blank">Telegram</a> channel for the latest updates on news you need to know.</p>
        <hr/>
    </div><p>KUALA LUMPUR, April 11 — The Ministry of Finance (MoF) today clarified that MKD Signature Sdn Bhd (MSSB), a company owned by Minister of Finance (Incorporated) [MoF (Inc)] is still the major shareholder of Mulia Property Development Sdn Bhd (MPDSB).</p><p>“Currently, MSSB remains as the major shareholder of MPDSB and there has not been any share sale agreement with any party,” it said in a statement dismissing a media report claiming MSSB had sold its shares.</p><p>MoF also explained that the decision to involve MSSB in the development of Exchange 106 was made to safeguard the interest of the TRX project, which was dragged into the 1Malaysia Development Bhd (1MDB) issue at that time after MPDSB failed to obtain a loan to finance the project.</p><p>It stressed that the sale of MSSB shares in MPDSB was subject to the Sale and Purchase Agreement and Shareholders’ Agreement entered into in 2017 whereby Mulia International Ltd (MIL) had the right to exercise Call Option to buy back 51 per cent of MSSB shares at an agreed price and upon settlement of the loan given by MSSB.</p><p>MSSB is a MoF (Inc) company within MPDSB which owns the Exchange 106 building in the Tun Razak Exchange (TRX) Project.</p><p>According to the ministry, MSSB acquired 51 per cent of shares in MPDSB on July 19, 2017 from MIL while another 49 per cent of the shares are still owned by the latter. — Bernama</p>
            ]]></content:encoded>
                        <dc:creator></dc:creator>
                        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 20:42:13 +0800</pubDate>
            <dc:subject>finance ministry,exchange 106,tun razak exchange project,mulia property development,mkd signature sdn bhd mssb</dc:subject>
        </item>
                <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Syed Saddiq says done with Singapore studies, raring to ‘rebuild Malaysia’, offers RM50,000 to Muar constituents]]></title>
            <link>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/11/syed-saddiq-says-done-with-singapore-studies-raring-to-rebuild-malaysia-off/1965687</link>
            <guid>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/11/syed-saddiq-says-done-with-singapore-studies-raring-to-rebuild-malaysia-off/1965687</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[KUALA LUMPUR, April 11 — Malaysia’s youngest parliamentarian Syed Saddiq Abdul Rahman today announced that he has completed his studies in Singapore and is looking forward to using what he learnt in the little red dot to serve his constituents...]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
                                <p><figure class="figure  float-left" style="width:800px">
        <img src="https://media2.malaymail.com/uploads/articles/2021/2021-04/syed_saddiq_abdul_rahman_certificate_20210411.jpg" class="figure-img img-fluid rounded" alt="Syed Saddiq Abdul Rahman announced that he has completed his Senior Fellowship at NUS Lee Kuan Yew School of Public Policy April 11, 2021. — Picture via Facebook/Syed Saddiq Syed Abdul Rahman" title="Syed Saddiq Abdul Rahman announced that he has completed his Senior Fellowship at NUS Lee Kuan Yew School of Public Policy April 11, 2021. — Picture via Facebook/Syed Saddiq Syed Abdul Rahman" width='800'  height='898'>
        <figcaption class="figure-caption">Syed Saddiq Abdul Rahman announced that he has completed his Senior Fellowship at NUS Lee Kuan Yew School of Public Policy April 11, 2021. — Picture via Facebook/Syed Saddiq Syed Abdul Rahman</figcaption>
    </figure>
    <div class="clearfix"></div>
    <div>
        <p class="font-italic">Subscribe to our <a class="font-weight-bold" href="https://t.me/themalaymail" target="_blank">Telegram</a> channel for the latest updates on news you need to know.</p>
        <hr/>
    </div><p>KUALA LUMPUR, April 11 — Malaysia’s youngest parliamentarian Syed Saddiq Abdul Rahman today announced that he has completed his studies in Singapore and is looking forward to using what he learnt in the little red dot to serve his constituents better.</p><p>The 28-year-old Muar MP, who had previously given up one month’s salary while on study leave, also said he will be donating his entire student allowance while in Singapore to the underprivileged in the Johor district.</p><p>“Alhamdulillah. Finally completed my Senior Fellowship at NUS Lee Kuan Yew School of Public Policy. I feel refreshed &amp; energised.</p><p>“I am looking forward to being an effective change-maker in Malaysia. Thank you to all who have helped me!</p><p>“As I promised, I have contributed one month of my salary for charitable purposes in Muar. When I was quarantined in Singapore, I also did a ‘fundraising’ through Zoom by teaching critical thinking classes. I was able to fundraise an additional RM20,000.</p><p>“I now would like to contribute 100 per cent of my Student Allowance (since I am under scholarship) throughout my stay in Singapore to the needy in Muar,” said Syed Saddiq on Facebook.</p><p>Overall, Syed Saddiq’s salary, fundraising efforts and student allowance amount to RM50,000, which he said will be used to help the underprivileged in Muar.</p><p>“I want the best for Muar.</p><p>“Hopefully the knowledge that I have learned will help improve my capabilities to serve Muar and Malaysia. Let’s rebuild Malaysia together!” he said.</p><p><iframe allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="true" frameborder="0" height="678" scrolling="no" src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2Fsyedsaddiqofficial%2Fposts%2F3843676779044653&amp;width=500&amp;show_text=true&amp;height=678&amp;appId" style="border:none;overflow:hidden" width="500"></iframe></p><p>The former youth and sports minister previously said he was registered for an executive course on public policy at the National University of Singapore since September last year.</p><p>In March, he said he was required to attend physical classes at the university to complete the programme.</p><p>Because of that, he said he will forego his salary for the month while he is based in Singapore fo his studies.</p>
            ]]></content:encoded>
                        <dc:creator>Danial Dzulkifly</dc:creator>
                        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 19:43:38 +0800</pubDate>
            <dc:subject>constituents,muar,syed saddiq syed abdul rahman</dc:subject>
        </item>
                <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cook in Penang under murder probe after wife falls 18th floors from home window]]></title>
            <link>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/11/cook-in-penang-under-murder-probe-after-wife-falls-18th-floors-from-home-wi/1965685</link>
            <guid>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/11/cook-in-penang-under-murder-probe-after-wife-falls-18th-floors-from-home-wi/1965685</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[GEORGE TOWN, April 11 — A woman who was found dead on the roof of a Tenaga Nasional Bhd (TNB) electric switch panel room at Bukit Awana condominium, Air Itam here was allegedly pushed out of the living room window of her 18th floor home by her...]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
                                <p><figure class="figure  float-left" style="width:800px">
        <img src="https://media2.malaymail.com/uploads/articles/2019/2019-03/pdrm_logo_generic0603b.jpg" class="figure-img img-fluid rounded" alt="Police received information on the discovery of the body of the 35-year-old woman who was allegedly pushed out of 18th floor living room yesterday by her husband at the Bukit Awana condominium in Air Itam. ― Picture by Hari Anggara" title="Police received information on the discovery of the body of the 35-year-old woman who was allegedly pushed out of 18th floor living room yesterday by her husband at the Bukit Awana condominium in Air Itam. ― Picture by Hari Anggara" width='800'  height='534'>
        <figcaption class="figure-caption">Police received information on the discovery of the body of the 35-year-old woman who was allegedly pushed out of 18th floor living room yesterday by her husband at the Bukit Awana condominium in Air Itam. ― Picture by Hari Anggara</figcaption>
    </figure>
    <div class="clearfix"></div>
    <div>
        <p class="font-italic">Subscribe to our <a class="font-weight-bold" href="https://t.me/themalaymail" target="_blank">Telegram</a> channel for the latest updates on news you need to know.</p>
        <hr/>
    </div><p>GEORGE TOWN, April 11 — A woman who was found dead on the roof of a Tenaga Nasional Bhd (TNB) electric switch panel room at Bukit Awana condominium, Air Itam here was allegedly pushed out of the living room window of her 18th floor home by her husband.</p><p>Timur Laut district police chief, ACP Soffian Santong said police received information on the discovery of the body of the 35-year-old woman yesterday at 12.06am before investigating the case and detaining the husband half an hour later at their home.</p><p>“The body of the victim, who worked as an insurance agent, was found by residents there covered with blood, and her husband, who is a cook at an eatery, admitted to shoving her during a fight when questioned by police.</p><p>“The couple were arguing at their home on the 18th floor because the suspect was allegedly jealous of the wife, whom he suspected was having an affair with another man,” he said when contacted today.</p><p>Soffian said following the arrest, police seized two mobile phones and a bottle containing crystals and a plastic packet suspected to contain drugs used by the suspect.</p><p>He said the man tested positive for drugs and was now being remanded for six days to facilitate the investigation under Section 302 of the Penal Code for murder.</p><p>Meanwhile, Soffian said police received a report from a man that he found a male baby abandoned in front of the Penang Family Health Development Association office in Jelutong around 7.40 pm yesterday.</p><p>The 43-year-old man said he found the baby, who still had his umbilical cord attached, when he opened the door of the office from inside, with a note stating, “Please take care of this baby”.</p><p>“The man then brought the baby into the office and ensured it was clothed and fed,” he said, adding that the baby was then handed over to Penang General Hospital.</p><p>Anyone with information on this case or the parents of the baby are urged to contact the investigating officer at 019-473 5105 or any nearby police station to assist the investigation. — Bernama</p>
            ]]></content:encoded>
                        <dc:creator></dc:creator>
                        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 19:21:28 +0800</pubDate>
            <dc:subject>pdrm,penang police,fall to death</dc:subject>
        </item>
                <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SDMC releases SOP for breaking of fast in restaurants, halls, hotels and food premises]]></title>
            <link>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/11/sdmc-releases-sop-for-breaking-of-fast-in-restaurants-halls-hotels-and-food/1965681</link>
            <guid>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/11/sdmc-releases-sop-for-breaking-of-fast-in-restaurants-halls-hotels-and-food/1965681</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[KUCHING, April 11 —The Sarawak Disaster Management Committee has released the detailed standard operating procedure (SOP) for the breaking of fast in restaurants, halls, hotels and food premises. The committee said the organisers for the breaking...]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
                                <p><figure class="figure  float-left" style="width:800px">
        <img src="https://media2.malaymail.com/uploads/articles/2021/2021-04/20210411sop_pkpb.jpeg" class="figure-img img-fluid rounded" alt="Among the new SOPs was that the breaking of fast could only take place at a venue at 50 per cent of its capacity. — Picture via Borneo Post Online" title="Among the new SOPs was that the breaking of fast could only take place at a venue at 50 per cent of its capacity. — Picture via Borneo Post Online" width='800'  height='450'>
        <figcaption class="figure-caption">Among the new SOPs was that the breaking of fast could only take place at a venue at 50 per cent of its capacity. — Picture via Borneo Post Online</figcaption>
    </figure>
    <div class="clearfix"></div>
    <div>
        <p class="font-italic">Subscribe to our <a class="font-weight-bold" href="https://t.me/themalaymail" target="_blank">Telegram</a> channel for the latest updates on news you need to know.</p>
        <hr/>
    </div><p>KUCHING, April 11 —The Sarawak Disaster Management Committee has released the detailed standard operating procedure (SOP) for the breaking of fast in restaurants, halls, hotels and food premises.</p><p>The committee said the organisers for the breaking of fast must inform the local authorities and their respective divisional disaster management committee (JPBB) prior to holding the activities</p><p>“The local authorities will carry out inspections with the respective JPBB and Ministry of Health before a written approval is issued by the JPBB,” said the committee.</p><p>It said the breaking of fast could only take place at a venue at 50 per cent of its capacity with physical distancing being observed or a maximum of 300 persons only.</p><p>“It is compulsory for customers to make reservations before dining at the premises. Walk-in customers are not allowed.”</p><p>The committee said group reservation by government agency or private sector is not allowed and it is only allowed for individuals and those involving closest family members.</p><p>Customers are not allowed to wait in-line and orders to be made by customers from the menu and food to be served on the table, it added.</p><p>It also stressed the organiser has to implement self-enforcement for all the SOP listed out.</p><p>Furthermore, the committee said the premises’ entry and exit pathways must be clearly labelled, as well as the perimeter of the area where the breaking of fast is taking place must be indicated, particularly if it is held at an open area or dining hall.</p><p>“Registration counters have to be set up at the entrance to limit the number of attendees, to check on a customer’s body temperature and any symptoms of coughing, sore throat, experiencing a cold and breathing difficulties. Customer whose body temperature is above 37.5 degree Celsius or exhibiting symptoms is not allowed to enter.”</p><p>“The organisers, operators, crew, waiter or workers must undergo health screening, not showing any symptoms of sickness and masks wearing is compulsory at all times.”</p><p>Customers or diners have to maintain a physical distancing of one metre while queueing at the registration counter.</p><p>“The entry into the premise must be strictly monitored and the attendance of the customers inside the dining area must adhere to the SOPs in place.”</p><p>It said the staff or crew members at the registration counters have to make sure the customers wash their hands with soap, hand wash or hand sanitiser before entering the premises.</p><p>Moreover, the committee said a through cleaning and disinfection in accordance to the Ministry of Health’s SOP must be conducted before and after the breaking of fast event at the dining area, tables and chairs, catering utensils, toilets and any surfaces or items that are prone to being touched.</p><p>“The location for the breaking of fast must also enjoy good ventilation and a distance of one metre between dining tables. The preparation of food must be in the form of pack food, served or dome setting. Crew members or waiters must put on their face mask and gloves when handling the food.”</p><p>Customers or diners must adhere to the instructions of the organisers or operators in accordance to the SOP set up by the committee and they must be wearing face mask at all times, it added.</p><p>“Individuals who are suffering from chronic illness are advised not to participate in the breaking of fast activity at the mentioned premises. Attendance from babies and children are also discouraged.”</p><p>The committee also pointed out the organisers or operators must keep the attendance of the customers and staff members in record via MySejahtera or manually by taking down the name, telephone number, date and time of an individual should a place has no Internet connection.</p><p>It said customers must also take their seats as indicated by the organiser or operator and they should avoid close conversation and moving from table to table.</p><p>“Customers must dine-in with physical distancing in place and not in group. Congestion at the toilet, lift or at any area where the breaking of fast is taking place should be avoided.”</p><p>Customers are also urged not to congregate outside the dining area before and after the breaking of fast, as well as exiting the dining area in an orderly manner.</p><p>The committee said If any operator, worker or customer has been detected to be Covid-19 positive, the dining area must be closed immediately for sanitation to take place.</p><p>“As for breaking of fast at mosque or surau, it will be based on the approvals issued and the SOP listed out by the state Islamic authorities.”</p><p>The committee warned any organiser or customers who do obey the SOP stipulated will be compounded under the existing laws and regulations.</p><p>Among the activities not allowed included moving from table to table for greetings, breaking of fasts in area where crowd control would be difficult, buffet services, travelling to areas under Recovery Movement Control Order (MCO), Enhanced MCO and MCO, holding the breaking of fast event at MCO and Enhanced MCO areas and patient-under-investigation (PUI) and person-under-surveillance (PUS) are not allowed to attend the event.</p><p>The breaking of fast event will continued to be governed by the latest regulations under State Disaster Management Committee and the local authorities from time to time, as well as the Food Hygiene Regulations 2009.</p><p>In another updated SOP by the committee, it said the operating hours for restaurants, food premises, food trucks and food delivery service, among other activities, have been extended to operate from 6am to 12am from the period of April 13 to 26. —&nbsp;Borneo Post Online</p>
            ]]></content:encoded>
                        <dc:creator></dc:creator>
                        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 19:08:24 +0800</pubDate>
            <dc:subject>sarawak,pandemic,covid-19,covid-19 sops</dc:subject>
        </item>
                <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SDMC has taken all ‘necessary steps’ to curb Covid-19 in Sarawak, says Uggah]]></title>
            <link>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/11/sdmc-has-taken-all-necessary-steps-to-curb-covid-19-in-sarawak-says-uggah/1965679</link>
            <guid>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/11/sdmc-has-taken-all-necessary-steps-to-curb-covid-19-in-sarawak-says-uggah/1965679</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[KUCHING, Apr 11 — The State Disaster Management Committee (SDMC) has taken all the necessary steps to curb the spread of Covid-19 in Sarawak, said its chairman Datuk Amar Douglas Uggah Embas. He explained that the committee’s role was mainly to...]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
                                <p><figure class="figure  float-left" style="width:800px">
        <img src="https://media2.malaymail.com/uploads/articles/2021/2021-01/amar_douglas_uggah_290121.jpg" class="figure-img img-fluid rounded" alt="Datuk Amar Douglas Uggah said the rising cases has led &#039;to some people blaming SDMC on social media for the rise in cases&#039;. ― Picture courtesy of Sarawak Information Department" title="Datuk Amar Douglas Uggah said the rising cases has led &#039;to some people blaming SDMC on social media for the rise in cases&#039;. ― Picture courtesy of Sarawak Information Department" width='800'  height='533'>
        <figcaption class="figure-caption">Datuk Amar Douglas Uggah said the rising cases has led 'to some people blaming SDMC on social media for the rise in cases'. ― Picture courtesy of Sarawak Information Department</figcaption>
    </figure>
    <div class="clearfix"></div>
    <div>
        <p class="font-italic">Subscribe to our <a class="font-weight-bold" href="https://t.me/themalaymail" target="_blank">Telegram</a> channel for the latest updates on news you need to know.</p>
        <hr/>
    </div><p>KUCHING, Apr 11 — The State Disaster Management Committee (SDMC) has taken all the necessary steps to curb the spread of Covid-19 in Sarawak, said its chairman Datuk Amar Douglas Uggah Embas.</p><p>He explained that the committee’s role was mainly to issue standard operating procedure (SOP) guidelines, enforce laws and monitor the implementation of SOPs while the Sarawak government has also provided the necessary allocation for operations to tackle the spread of the infectious disease.</p><p>“Once again, Covid-19 positive cases in Sarawak have increased significantly leading to some people blaming SDMC on social media for the rise in cases.</p><p>“Looking at the current situation, SDMC has taken steps and allocations have been provided by the government to curb the spread of Covid-19,” he told a press conference.</p><p>The Deputy Chief Minister pointed out that the situation can only be controlled with cooperation from all parties, including the local communities who each have their respective role to play to help stop the spread of Covid-19.</p><p>“SDMC has issued the guidelines for social events and these should always be complied with.</p><p>“Too many lives have been lost and victims have suffered as a result of this disease. That should be a lesson to all of us,” he stressed.</p><p>He also touched on the lockdown of villages across the state where 407 longhouses were placed under lockdown this year to the increasing number of Covid-19 cases.</p><p>“At present, only 48 longhouse areas are still under lockdown. This shows that the situation in rural areas seem to be under control.</p><p>“But whether this can continue or not depended on the people themselves as they must continue to adhere to the SOPs, remain cautious so that the virus does not spread in their respective areas,” he said.</p><p>With Sarawak being hit by three Covid-19 waves throughout last year, Uggah reiterated his call for the people to remain vigilant and engage in a ‘safety first’ attitude to ensure that the disease does not continue to spread.</p><p>“Please do not be complacent and careless and do take care of your health as well as your family. — Borneo Post Online</p>
            ]]></content:encoded>
                        <dc:creator></dc:creator>
                        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 19:03:32 +0800</pubDate>
            <dc:subject>douglas uggah embas,covid-19 sarawak,sarawak sdmc</dc:subject>
        </item>
                <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PSB president: Nothing much I could do when in Sarawak Cabinet due to minority]]></title>
            <link>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/11/psb-president-nothing-much-i-could-do-when-in-sarawak-cabinet-due-to-minori/1965677</link>
            <guid>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/11/psb-president-nothing-much-i-could-do-when-in-sarawak-cabinet-due-to-minori/1965677</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[KUCHING, April 11 — Parti Sarawak Bersatu (PSB) president Datuk Seri Wong Soon Koh said there was nothing much he could do when he was in the State Cabinet because he was always in a minority. He said based on the British (Westminster) model,...]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
                                <p><figure class="figure  float-left" style="width:800px">
        <img src="https://media2.malaymail.com/uploads/articles/2021/2021-04/Kch-bp100421-rm-WongPSB-1.jpeg" class="figure-img img-fluid rounded" alt="Datuk Seri Wong Soon Koh (centre) flanked by George Lo (right) and Johnical Rayong at the press conference April 11, 2021. — Picture by Chimon Upon/Borneo Post" title="Datuk Seri Wong Soon Koh (centre) flanked by George Lo (right) and Johnical Rayong at the press conference April 11, 2021. — Picture by Chimon Upon/Borneo Post" width='800'  height='534'>
        <figcaption class="figure-caption">Datuk Seri Wong Soon Koh (centre) flanked by George Lo (right) and Johnical Rayong at the press conference April 11, 2021. — Picture by Chimon Upon/Borneo Post</figcaption>
    </figure>
    <div class="clearfix"></div>
    <div>
        <p class="font-italic">Subscribe to our <a class="font-weight-bold" href="https://t.me/themalaymail" target="_blank">Telegram</a> channel for the latest updates on news you need to know.</p>
        <hr/>
    </div><p>KUCHING, April 11 — Parti Sarawak Bersatu (PSB) president Datuk Seri Wong Soon Koh said there was nothing much he could do when he was in the State Cabinet because he was always in a minority.</p><p>He said based on the British (Westminster) model, there was this collective decision and collective responsibility.</p><p>The state cabinet, he said, made the decision and if one person disagreed, the minority had to follow.</p><p>“I was always in the minority. And so if you are not happy, if you don’t want to follow, you just have to resign.</p><p>“So I resigned in order to break free my PSB as a party so that we can be independent and can do what we think is good for the people of Sarawak,” he told a press conference after launching the PSB Kota Sentosa branch office and Batu Kitang Service Centre and Kota Sentosa at Mile 7 here yesterday.</p><p>Wong said even during the heydays of the Sarawak United People’s Party (SUPP), the party which he was a part of, had always been the minority.</p><p>Earlier in his speech, Wong said he was aware that people were asking why hadn’t he talk about change, why hadn’t he talk about better government when he was holding a senior position in the cabinet for so long.</p><p>“Now, I would like to tell people that based on the Westminster’s model there is this collective decision and collective responsibility.</p><p>“Nothing much we can do. Minority must follow the majority,” he said.</p><p>Asked if PSB had decided on its candidates for Kota Sentosa and Batu Kitang, he said there were potential candidates, ‘but not confirmed yet’.</p><p>He said the party would confirm its final candidates for the two seats when the time comes.</p><p>“We know that people are all very anxious to know our candidates, but the final confirmation comes when they get the authorization letter (Surat Watikah).</p><p>“But it is obvious, for Batu Kitang we have Liu Thian Leong who has been moving around, and Datuk Dr John Lau for Kota Sentosa.</p><p>“They are our potential candidates for the moment. When the time comes, we will confirm them,” he said.</p><p>PSB secretary general George Lo and vice president Johnical Rayong were also present at the function. — Borneo Post</p>
            ]]></content:encoded>
                        <dc:creator></dc:creator>
                        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 18:57:10 +0800</pubDate>
            <dc:subject>wong soon koh,sarawak cabinet,parti sarawak bersatu psb</dc:subject>
        </item>
                <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Covid-19: Sarawak’s cumulative tally climbs past 20,000 after recording 443 new cases today]]></title>
            <link>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/11/covid-19-sarawaks-cumulative-tally-climbs-past-20000-after-recording-443-ne/1965675</link>
            <guid>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/11/covid-19-sarawaks-cumulative-tally-climbs-past-20000-after-recording-443-ne/1965675</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[KUCHING, Apr 11 — Sarawak’s Covid-19 cases breached the 20,000 mark today after it recorded another 443 new positive cases, said State Disaster Management Committee (SDMC) chairman Datuk Amar Douglas Uggah Embas. He said Bintulu topped the list...]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
                                <p><figure class="figure  float-left" style="width:800px">
        <img src="https://media2.malaymail.com/uploads/articles/2021/2021-04/20210411_ppe_borneopost.jpeg" class="figure-img img-fluid rounded" alt="The total number of positive cases in Sarawak has now increased to 20,001. — Photo by Chimon Upon" title="The total number of positive cases in Sarawak has now increased to 20,001. — Photo by Chimon Upon" width='800'  height='534'>
        <figcaption class="figure-caption">The total number of positive cases in Sarawak has now increased to 20,001. — Photo by Chimon Upon</figcaption>
    </figure>
    <div class="clearfix"></div>
    <div>
        <p class="font-italic">Subscribe to our <a class="font-weight-bold" href="https://t.me/themalaymail" target="_blank">Telegram</a> channel for the latest updates on news you need to know.</p>
        <hr/>
    </div><p>KUCHING, Apr 11 — Sarawak’s Covid-19 cases breached the 20,000 mark today after it recorded another 443 new positive cases, said State Disaster Management Committee (SDMC) chairman Datuk Amar Douglas Uggah Embas.</p><p>He said Bintulu topped the list with 89 cases followed by Sibu (83), Miri (61), Julau (43), Kapit (32), Mukah (31), Kuching (26), and Sarikei (22).</p><p>“There were also 15 districts which recorded single-digit cases namely Matu (7), Samarahan (7), Meradong (7), Subis (6), Serian (6), Kabong (5), Beluru (3), Belaga (3), Betong (3), Bukit Mabong (3), Kanowit (2), Saratok (1), Tanjung Manis (1), Tatau (1) and Sebauh (1).</p><p>“The total number of positive cases in the state has now increased to 20,001,” he told a press conference. — Borneo Post Online</p><img  alt=""  height="693"  src="https://media2.malaymail.com/uploads/articles/2021/2021-04/COVID19_Current_status_Malaysia_Apr11-2021.jpg"  style="width:800px"  width="800"  title=""  caption=""  class=" float-left"  ><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
            ]]></content:encoded>
                        <dc:creator></dc:creator>
                        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 18:53:16 +0800</pubDate>
            <dc:subject>sarawak,borneo post online</dc:subject>
        </item>
                <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rescuers retrieve body of man believed to be shot by brother during hunting trip gone wrong in Sarawak]]></title>
            <link>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/11/rescuers-retrieve-body-of-man-believed-to-be-shot-by-brother-during-hunting/1965674</link>
            <guid>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/11/rescuers-retrieve-body-of-man-believed-to-be-shot-by-brother-during-hunting/1965674</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[KUCHING, April 11 — The body of a 55-year-old man who is believed to have died from gunshot wounds in the jungle near Kampung Stenggang, Jalan Bau-Lundu has been retrieved by the Fire and Rescue Department personnel at around 1.50am today. Bau...]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
                                <p><figure class="figure  float-left" style="width:800px">
        <img src="https://media2.malaymail.com/uploads/articles/2021/2021-04/sarawak_jungle_shooting_body_20210411.jpeg" class="figure-img img-fluid rounded" alt="Bomba personnel securing the deceased’s body on a stretcher before it was brought out of the jungle April 11, 2021. — Borneo Post pic" title="Bomba personnel securing the deceased’s body on a stretcher before it was brought out of the jungle April 11, 2021. — Borneo Post pic" width='800'  height='561'>
        <figcaption class="figure-caption">Bomba personnel securing the deceased’s body on a stretcher before it was brought out of the jungle April 11, 2021. — Borneo Post pic</figcaption>
    </figure>
    <div class="clearfix"></div>
    <div>
        <p class="font-italic">Subscribe to our <a class="font-weight-bold" href="https://t.me/themalaymail" target="_blank">Telegram</a> channel for the latest updates on news you need to know.</p>
        <hr/>
    </div><p>KUCHING, April 11 — The body of a 55-year-old man who is believed to have died from gunshot wounds in the jungle near Kampung Stenggang, Jalan Bau-Lundu has been retrieved by the Fire and Rescue Department personnel at around 1.50am today.</p><p>Bau Fire Station Chief Tawang Lingem said the deceased, identified as Nohen Pates, is believed to have been accidently shot by his own brother during a hunting trip in the jungle last night.</p><p>“It took Bomba personnel around 20 minutes to reach the opening by a river where the deceased was found with buckshot wounds to his chest,” said Tawang in a statement today.</p><p>He added that a call informing them of the incident was received at 11.47pm last night.</p><p>A team from the Bau fire station arrived at the scene at 1.20am and started the operation together with five villagers and five police personnel.</p><p>The body of the deceased was then carried out of the jungle with a bucket stretcher.</p><p>The body has since been handed over to the Bau district police for further action and the operation ended at 2.48am. — Borneo Post</p>
            ]]></content:encoded>
                        <dc:creator></dc:creator>
                        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 18:50:13 +0800</pubDate>
            <dc:subject>sarawak,accidental shooting</dc:subject>
        </item>
                <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kedah, Perak religious authorities to step up enforcement during Ramadan]]></title>
            <link>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/11/kedah-perak-religious-authorities-to-step-up-enforcement-during-ramadan/1965671</link>
            <guid>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/11/kedah-perak-religious-authorities-to-step-up-enforcement-during-ramadan/1965671</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[ALOR SETAR, April 11 — The Kedah Islamic Religious Affairs Department (JHEAIK) will increase monitoring at 71 restaurants and eateries in the state known to be frequent haunts for those who skip fasting during Ramadan. State Religious, Education...]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
                                    <p><img src="https://www.malaymail.com/graphics/meta/main/logo-310x150.png" alt="Malay Mail Social Logo" /></p>
                                <p>ALOR SETAR, April 11 — The Kedah Islamic Religious Affairs Department (JHEAIK) will increase monitoring at 71 restaurants and eateries in the state known to be frequent haunts for those who skip fasting during Ramadan.</p><p>State Religious, Education and Human Resource committee chairman Brig Gen (R) Datuk Najmi Ahmad said 200 JHEAIK enforcement personnel and officers will be mobilised to monitor and take action against individuals and businesses involved.</p><p>“Usually, businesses that operate during the fasting month are the same people every year and it might be their habit every Ramadan (to sell food and drink to those who skip fasting),” he said at a media conference here today.</p><p>Non-Muslim premises will also be monitored as there are Muslim traders who offer food and drink to those who skip their fast there in an effort to avoid detection by enforcement officers, he added.</p><p>Najmi said businesses that operate during non-reasonable hours (before from 3 or 4pm) throughout Ramadan will have action taken against them.</p><p>He also reminded Muslims in the state not to be involved in any gambling activities and hoped that they would channel information regarding such activities to the police so that action can be taken.</p><p>Meanwhile, in IPOH, the Perak Islamic Religious Department (JAIPk) has identified at least three main locations where the ‘black plastic gang’ in the city will frequent during Ramadan. Named after the black plastic bags used to hide the food carried in them, these individuals have no qualms of buying food and drink from any business willing to provide them during Ramadan.&nbsp;</p><p>JAIPk director Datuk Mohd Yusof Husin said his department had prepared 100 enforcement personnel to raid these locations and detain anyone who was found to be skipping their fast, no matter what their excuse.</p><p>“These black plastic gang individuals will make excuses, claiming to be buying food for other people, the elderly and sick.</p><p>“We usually advise them because the most popular excuse used is they are hungry and dying for a smoke. But sterner action will be taken if they are caught for skipping their fast,” he said after presenting school uniforms to 100 students from B40 families today.</p><p>According to him, any Muslim found guilty of drinking or eating in public throughout Ramadan can be fined RM1,000 or jailed for six months, or both, adding that the issue was not something new but kept on reoccurring every year.</p><p>“So I urge all Muslims to uphold their dignity and that of Islam and do not bring disrepute to all devout Muslims,” he said. — Bernama</p>
            ]]></content:encoded>
                        <dc:creator></dc:creator>
                        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 18:45:28 +0800</pubDate>
            <dc:subject>perak,kedah,ramadan</dc:subject>
        </item>
                <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cuepacs urges govt to review civil service pay system amid Covid hardship]]></title>
            <link>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/11/cuepacs-wants-govt-to-review-malaysias-civil-service-remuneration-system-to/1965670</link>
            <guid>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/11/cuepacs-wants-govt-to-review-malaysias-civil-service-remuneration-system-to/1965670</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[KUALA LUMPUR, April 11 — The Congress of Unions of Employees in the Public and Civil Services (Cuepacs) has called on the government to review the Malaysian Remuneration System (SSM) used by the civil service to meet the current economic needs and...]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
                                <p><figure class="figure  float-left" style="width:800px">
        <img src="https://media2.malaymail.com/uploads/articles/2020/2020-09/cuepacs_adnan_mat_300920.jpg" class="figure-img img-fluid rounded" alt="Cuepacs president Adnan Mat speaks at the State Forestry Department Headquarters in Meru September 30, 2020. ― Picture by Farhan Najib" title="Cuepacs president Adnan Mat speaks at the State Forestry Department Headquarters in Meru September 30, 2020. ― Picture by Farhan Najib" width='800'  height='538'>
        <figcaption class="figure-caption">Cuepacs president Adnan Mat speaks at the State Forestry Department Headquarters in Meru September 30, 2020. ― Picture by Farhan Najib</figcaption>
    </figure>
    <div class="clearfix"></div>
    <div>
        <p class="font-italic">Subscribe to our <a class="font-weight-bold" href="https://t.me/themalaymail" target="_blank">Telegram</a> channel for the latest updates on news you need to know.</p>
        <hr/>
    </div><p>KUALA LUMPUR, April 11 — The Congress of Unions of Employees in the Public and Civil Services (Cuepacs) has called on the government to review the Malaysian Remuneration System (SSM) used by the civil service to meet the current economic needs and cost of living.</p><p>Cuepacs president Adnan Mat in a statement today said the SSM had not been reviewed or improved since its implementation in November 2002.</p><p>“The review of SSM needs to be done immediately as the scheme was formulated based on the economic situation and cost of living in 2002 and now it can be considered no longer relevant.</p><p>“In the last 19 years, we have faced the rising cost of living, including a sharp increase in prices of houses,” read the statement.</p><p>He said the current starting salary in the government sector is RM1,200 excluding other allowances and it was still far below the country’s new poverty line income (PGK) of RM2,208, adding that among the things that needed to be emphasised in the new SSM was the setting of a minimum salary of RM1,800.</p><p>“Cuepacs is ready to hold talks and discussions with the government to review and renew the SSM.</p><p>“A drastic action needs to be taken to review SSM so that the government’s intention to improve the quality of public sector delivery services can be done more effectively,” he said. — Bernama</p>
            ]]></content:encoded>
                        <dc:creator></dc:creator>
                        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 18:39:24 +0800</pubDate>
            <dc:subject>cuepacs,malaysian remuneration system ssm,malaysian civil service,congress of unions of employees in the public and civil services malaysia</dc:subject>
        </item>
                <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Penang South Reclamation project expected to start in May or June, says deputy CM]]></title>
            <link>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/11/penang-south-reclamation-project-expected-to-start-in-may-or-june-says-depu/1965669</link>
            <guid>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/11/penang-south-reclamation-project-expected-to-start-in-may-or-june-says-depu/1965669</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[GEORGE TOWN, April 11 — The state government is committed to implementing the Penang South Reclamation (PSR) project which is expected to start in late May or early June. Deputy Chief Minister I, Datuk Ahmad Zakiyuddin Abd Rahman said the coastal...]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
                                <p><figure class="figure  float-left" style="width:800px">
        <img src="https://media2.malaymail.com/uploads/articles/2019/2019-11/Ahmad_Zakiyuddin_Abdul_Rahman2_0711.jpg" class="figure-img img-fluid rounded" alt="Penang Deputy Chief Minister I Datuk Ahmad Zakiyuddin Abdul Rahman is pictured at Dewan Sri Pinang, George Town November 7, 2019. — Picture by Sayuti Zainudin" title="Penang Deputy Chief Minister I Datuk Ahmad Zakiyuddin Abdul Rahman is pictured at Dewan Sri Pinang, George Town November 7, 2019. — Picture by Sayuti Zainudin" width='800'  height='508'>
        <figcaption class="figure-caption">Penang Deputy Chief Minister I Datuk Ahmad Zakiyuddin Abdul Rahman is pictured at Dewan Sri Pinang, George Town November 7, 2019. — Picture by Sayuti Zainudin</figcaption>
    </figure>
    <div class="clearfix"></div>
    <div>
        <p class="font-italic">Subscribe to our <a class="font-weight-bold" href="https://t.me/themalaymail" target="_blank">Telegram</a> channel for the latest updates on news you need to know.</p>
        <hr/>
    </div><p>GEORGE TOWN, April 11 — The state government is committed to implementing the Penang South Reclamation (PSR) project which is expected to start in late May or early June.</p><p>Deputy Chief Minister I, Datuk Ahmad Zakiyuddin Abd Rahman said the coastal reclamation work would begin once the Environmental Management Plan (EMP) has been approved, expected to be in May.</p><p>“The Department of Environment has a standard operating procedure (SOP) and they are professional in their work approach. There is no reason for us to speculate (that the EMP will be denied),” he said at a news conference after visiting the Island A reclamation site today.</p><p>The visit covered three locations at Island A, namely, where the reclamation work starts, the southernmost part and the westernmost.</p><p>He said the visit to the first location was to see the distance between the new island and the existing beach area, which is about 300 metres, while the distance between the latter and southernmost location of the reclaimed island is about 4 km.</p><p>Under the PSR project, the state government has proposed the development of reclaimed sea area of 1,821 hectares, including the creation of three man-made islands from the waters of Permatang Damar Laut. to Gertak Sanggul. — Bernama</p>
            ]]></content:encoded>
                        <dc:creator></dc:creator>
                        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 18:33:05 +0800</pubDate>
            <dc:subject>penang south reclamation project,zakiyuddin abdul rahman</dc:subject>
        </item>
                <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sarawakians remember Prince Philip’s visit to Miri in 1959]]></title>
            <link>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/11/sarawakians-remember-prince-philips-visit-to-miri-in-1959/1965668</link>
            <guid>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/11/sarawakians-remember-prince-philips-visit-to-miri-in-1959/1965668</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[MIRI, April 11 — Many Mirians, especially those more senior in age, took to social media to mourn the passing of Prince Philip, beloved husband of Queen Elizabeth II. The Duke of Edinburgh died on Friday at the age of 99. Among those who shared...]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
                                <p><figure class="figure  float-left" style="width:800px">
        <img src="https://media2.malaymail.com/uploads/articles/2021/2021-04/Myy-bp10042021-cl-princephilip-remembering-p1.jpg" class="figure-img img-fluid rounded" alt="An old photo shared by Chang Yi on Facebook shows Prince Philip waving to the crowd from the motorcade when he visited Miri. — Picture via Borneo Post" title="An old photo shared by Chang Yi on Facebook shows Prince Philip waving to the crowd from the motorcade when he visited Miri. — Picture via Borneo Post" width='800'  height='606'>
        <figcaption class="figure-caption">An old photo shared by Chang Yi on Facebook shows Prince Philip waving to the crowd from the motorcade when he visited Miri. — Picture via Borneo Post</figcaption>
    </figure>
    <div class="clearfix"></div>
    <div>
        <p class="font-italic">Subscribe to our <a class="font-weight-bold" href="https://t.me/themalaymail" target="_blank">Telegram</a> channel for the latest updates on news you need to know.</p>
        <hr/>
    </div><p>MIRI, April 11 — Many Mirians, especially those more senior in age, took to social media to mourn the passing of Prince Philip, beloved husband of Queen Elizabeth II.</p><p>The Duke of Edinburgh died on Friday at the age of 99.</p><p>Among those who shared their cherished memories was Christopher S. Jiram who recalled the visit of His Royal Highness (HRH) to Miri in 1959.</p><p>“The visit was announced by our principal during school assembly. I was 13 years old at the time,” he told The Borneo Post yesterday.</p><p>The colonial government, he remembered, hired a few buses to transport Tanjong Lobang School students to an open concert organised by the Resident at the then GCM Padang.</p><p>“The open concert was to entertain HRH during his visit here. As I missed the bus at the end of the concert, I got a lift from my teacher George Ong.</p><p>“His Royal Highness’ visit to Miri at the time, must have coincided with the Chinese New Year, as I remembered having visited a few Chinese houses,” shared Christopher.</p><p>“The next morning, we were made to line up along the road at the entrance of his residency to bid the Duke farewell.</p><p>“Due to the crowd, and my height, I was only able to see his famous hat as the motorcade passed by,” he recalled.</p><p>Bill Liao also shared his recollections of the visit 62 years ago.</p><p>“My father was a Miri councillor then and he had a photo shaking hands with Prince Philip. Sadly, we have lost the photo,” he wrote.</p><p>Awang Draup was another Mirian who said he was among those lining up along the road to catch a glimpse of HRH.</p><p>Prince Philip made a 41-hour visit to Sarawak in 1959. He arrived in Kuching, proceeded to Sibu and then Miri as final stop before heading to Brunei. — Borneo Post</p>
            ]]></content:encoded>
                        <dc:creator></dc:creator>
                        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 18:29:51 +0800</pubDate>
            <dc:subject>sarawak,prince philip death</dc:subject>
        </item>
                <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vet Services Dept assures Malaysians of sufficient food supply throughout Ramadan, Hari Raya]]></title>
            <link>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/11/vet-services-dept-assures-malaysians-of-sufficient-food-supply-throughout-r/1965667</link>
            <guid>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/11/vet-services-dept-assures-malaysians-of-sufficient-food-supply-throughout-r/1965667</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[JASIN, April 11 — The supply of meat, milk, poultry and eggs in the country is guaranteed to be sufficient, not only to meet consumer demand during Ramadan but also for Hari Raya Aidilfitri and Hari Raya Aidiladha. Veterinary Services Department...]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
                                <p><figure class="figure  float-left" style="width:800px">
        <img src="https://media2.malaymail.com/uploads/articles/2016-12/Eggs_31122016.jpg" class="figure-img img-fluid rounded" alt="The supply of meat, milk, poultry and eggs in the country is guaranteed to be sufficient, not only to meet consumer demand during Ramadan but also for Hari Raya Aidilfitri and Hari Raya Aidiladha. — Reuters pic" title="The supply of meat, milk, poultry and eggs in the country is guaranteed to be sufficient, not only to meet consumer demand during Ramadan but also for Hari Raya Aidilfitri and Hari Raya Aidiladha. — Reuters pic" width='800'  height='533'>
        <figcaption class="figure-caption">The supply of meat, milk, poultry and eggs in the country is guaranteed to be sufficient, not only to meet consumer demand during Ramadan but also for Hari Raya Aidilfitri and Hari Raya Aidiladha. — Reuters pic</figcaption>
    </figure>
    <div class="clearfix"></div>
    <div>
        <p class="font-italic">Subscribe to our <a class="font-weight-bold" href="https://t.me/themalaymail" target="_blank">Telegram</a> channel for the latest updates on news you need to know.</p>
        <hr/>
    </div><p>JASIN, April 11 — The supply of meat, milk, poultry and eggs in the country is guaranteed to be sufficient, not only to meet consumer demand during Ramadan but also for Hari Raya Aidilfitri and Hari Raya Aidiladha.</p><p>Veterinary Services Department (JPV) director-general Datuk Dr Norlizan Mohd Noor said since January this year, importers had obtained a lot of frozen meat supplies, namely buffalo from India and beef from Australia, New Zealand and Pakistan.</p><p>He said the importation of beef and buffalo meat from abroad still played an important role as Malaysia still relied on imported sources to ensure continued supply.</p><p>“In addition, we have a committee that monitors this matter and God-willing, the supply is sufficient and can meet consumer needs not only during the month of Ramadan and Syawal but also for the next two months.</p><p>“For example, there are also some cattle farmers who have stocked up on sacrificial cows some three to four months in advance, so consumers do not have to worry,” he told Bernama, here.</p><p>Elaborating, Norlizan said to ensure food security such as for meat, around 210,000 metric tonnes of cows and buffaloes are needed a year to meet consumer needs.</p><p>He said, however, for local meat production, the country was only able to produce 46,000 metric tonnes or about 22 per cent last year, from livestock resources available in the country.</p><p>He added that JPV had formulated various programmes and efforts to increase the country’s meat production, including the “Beef Plan” since 2019, apart from working closely with the Malaysian Agricultural Research and Development Institute (Mardi).</p><p>“There are four main activities carried out in the farming programme namely feedlot; integrated farming such as the Kedah-Kelantan Elite (KK Elite) cattle breed; conventional farming namely small-scale and independent farming; and dairy contribution.</p><p>“In the 12th Malaysia Plan, we have developed many schemes to increase beef cattle production and aim to achieve 30 per cent by 2025,” he added. — Bernama</p>
            ]]></content:encoded>
                        <dc:creator></dc:creator>
                        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 18:24:22 +0800</pubDate>
            <dc:subject>ramadan,veterinary services department,food supply,hari raya aidilfitri 2021</dc:subject>
        </item>
                <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Terengganu Health Dept: Covid-19 screening extended to two more villages in Hulu Besut]]></title>
            <link>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/11/terengganu-health-dept-covid-19-screening-extended-to-two-more-villages-in/1965665</link>
            <guid>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/11/terengganu-health-dept-covid-19-screening-extended-to-two-more-villages-in/1965665</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[BESUT, April 11 —The Covid-19 screening programme has been extended to two villages located close to the areas placed under enhanced movement control order (EMCO) in Hulu Besut. State Health Department director Dr Nor Azimi Yunus said since...]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
                                <p><figure class="figure  float-left" style="width:800px">
        <img src="https://media2.malaymail.com/uploads/articles/2021/2021-02/2802_swab_test_20210228FL2.JPG" class="figure-img img-fluid rounded" alt="Healthcare workers are seen during a Covid-19 swab test in Petaling Jaya February 28, 2021. — Picture by Firdaus Latif" title="Healthcare workers are seen during a Covid-19 swab test in Petaling Jaya February 28, 2021. — Picture by Firdaus Latif" width='800'  height='534'>
        <figcaption class="figure-caption">Healthcare workers are seen during a Covid-19 swab test in Petaling Jaya February 28, 2021. — Picture by Firdaus Latif</figcaption>
    </figure>
    <div class="clearfix"></div>
    <div>
        <p class="font-italic">Subscribe to our <a class="font-weight-bold" href="https://t.me/themalaymail" target="_blank">Telegram</a> channel for the latest updates on news you need to know.</p>
        <hr/>
    </div><p>BESUT, April 11 —The Covid-19 screening programme has been extended to two villages located close to the areas placed under enhanced movement control order (EMCO) in Hulu Besut.</p><p>State Health Department director Dr Nor Azimi Yunus said since yesterday, screenings have been conducted in Kampung Pak Sik and Felcra Keruak located near Kampung Belaoh, Kampung Keruak and the Belaoh Baru PPRT which have been under EMCO since last Wednesday, after the Belaoh Cluster was detected.</p><p>“The screening programme at the two villages will involve 1,094 residents as some of them have been in contact with people in the three villages placed under EMCO,” she told reporters after monitoring the screening process at Sekolah Kebangsaan (SK) Keruak today.</p><p>Nor Azimi does not rule out the possibility that there would be an increase in positive cases in the five villages following the ongoing screenings.</p><p>“Currently, the infectivity rate (Rt) in Terengganu is 1.53 but two weeks ago the state recorded the lowest Rt at 0.53,” she said.</p><p>The Belaoh cluster identified on April 6, is a community cluster involving Besut and Marang districts in Terengganu and Bachok district in Kelantan. — Bernama</p>
            ]]></content:encoded>
                        <dc:creator></dc:creator>
                        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 18:18:49 +0800</pubDate>
            <dc:subject>terengganu,covid-19,covid-19 testing,hulu besut</dc:subject>
        </item>
                <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Perak CM keen to revive Commonwealth Youth City project in Tg Malim that Pakatan froze]]></title>
            <link>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/11/perak-cm-keen-to-revive-commonwealth-youth-city-project-in-tg-malim-that-pa/1965663</link>
            <guid>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/11/perak-cm-keen-to-revive-commonwealth-youth-city-project-in-tg-malim-that-pa/1965663</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[IPOH, April 11 — The Perak government will revive the Commonwealth Youth City project in Tanjung Malim that was shelved during Pakatan Harapan’s rule. Mentri Besar Datuk Saarani Mohamad said the project that was implemented under former Mentri...]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
                                <p><figure class="figure  float-left" style="width:800px">
        <img src="https://media2.malaymail.com/uploads/articles/2020/2020-12/FW1128146_PK03_1812020_BELANJAWAN_PERAK-lpr.jpg" class="figure-img img-fluid rounded" alt="Perak Mentri Besar Datuk Saarani Mohamad speaks at the State Legislative Assembly in Ipoh December 18, 2020. — Bernama pic" title="Perak Mentri Besar Datuk Saarani Mohamad speaks at the State Legislative Assembly in Ipoh December 18, 2020. — Bernama pic" width='800'  height='538'>
        <figcaption class="figure-caption">Perak Mentri Besar Datuk Saarani Mohamad speaks at the State Legislative Assembly in Ipoh December 18, 2020. — Bernama pic</figcaption>
    </figure>
    <div class="clearfix"></div>
    <div>
        <p class="font-italic">Subscribe to our <a class="font-weight-bold" href="https://t.me/themalaymail" target="_blank">Telegram</a> channel for the latest updates on news you need to know.</p>
        <hr/>
    </div><p>IPOH, April 11 — The Perak government will revive the Commonwealth Youth City project in Tanjung Malim that was shelved during Pakatan Harapan’s rule.</p><p>Mentri Besar Datuk Saarani Mohamad said the project that was implemented under former Mentri Besar Datuk Seri Dr Zambry Abd Kadir’s administration, was part of plans for the Southern Perak Development Corridor.</p><p>“That plan was suspended after the new state government took over in 2018 and with its own policies introduced at that time, the project was shelved.</p><p>“Coincidently, when I was appointed Mentri Besar, the Northern Corridor Implementation Authority (NCIA) and the Northern Corridor Economic Region (NCER), which before this only focused on development in North Perak, agreed to expand its plans to the south as well.</p><p>He was speaking to reporters after presenting letters of appointment to Perak Youth Council members for the 2021-2022 term here today.</p><p>Saarani said the project would be revived because there were several public institutions of higher learning in the district, adding that the project was also expected to have a positive impact on Proton City in Tanjung Malim, which borders the Klang Valley.</p><p>“Selangor is also becoming increasingly congested, so they (investors) are moving industries to the Perak-Selangor border. So, we want to take advantage of this by focusing on developing Southern Perak,” he said.</p><p>Tanjung Malim had been earmarked before this to be developed as the site for the first Commonwealth Youth City project in the world, leveraging on existing public infrastructure and facilities and collaborations with the government, government-linked companies (GLCs), the private sector and the general public.</p><p>This visionary project was announced by Prince Charles, the Prince of Wales during the Commonwealth Youth Summit in November 2017, supported by the Malaysian government and the Perak government in collaboration with the Commonwealth Youth Innovation Centre and youth councils in Malaysia. — Bernama</p>
            ]]></content:encoded>
                        <dc:creator></dc:creator>
                        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 18:02:13 +0800</pubDate>
            <dc:subject>pakatan harapan,saarani mohamad,perak state government projects,commonwealth youth city</dc:subject>
        </item>
                <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Five days on, Selangor bomba still fighting container blaze off Pulau Carey]]></title>
            <link>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/11/five-days-on-selangor-bomba-still-fighting-container-blaze-off-pulau-carey/1965662</link>
            <guid>https://www.malaymail.com/news/malaysia/2021/04/11/five-days-on-selangor-bomba-still-fighting-container-blaze-off-pulau-carey/1965662</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[SHAH ALAM, April 11 — Efforts are still ongoing to put out the fire on 11 industrial goods containers, which have been ablaze on a cargo vessel in the Pulau Carey waters since last Wednesday. Selangor Fire and Rescue Department deputy director...]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
                                <p><figure class="figure  float-left" style="width:800px">
        <img src="https://media2.malaymail.com/uploads/articles/2021/2021-04/bernama_bomba_container_fire_20210.jpg" class="figure-img img-fluid rounded" alt="Selangor Fire and Rescue Department personnel in ongoing efforts to put out the fire on 11 industrial goods containers on a cargo vessel in the Pulau Carey waters April 11, 2021. — Picture via Twitter/Bernama" title="Selangor Fire and Rescue Department personnel in ongoing efforts to put out the fire on 11 industrial goods containers on a cargo vessel in the Pulau Carey waters April 11, 2021. — Picture via Twitter/Bernama" width='800'  height='642'>
        <figcaption class="figure-caption">Selangor Fire and Rescue Department personnel in ongoing efforts to put out the fire on 11 industrial goods containers on a cargo vessel in the Pulau Carey waters April 11, 2021. — Picture via Twitter/Bernama</figcaption>
    </figure>
    <div class="clearfix"></div>
    <div>
        <p class="font-italic">Subscribe to our <a class="font-weight-bold" href="https://t.me/themalaymail" target="_blank">Telegram</a> channel for the latest updates on news you need to know.</p>
        <hr/>
    </div><p>SHAH ALAM, April 11 — Efforts are still ongoing to put out the fire on 11 industrial goods containers, which have been ablaze on a cargo vessel in the Pulau Carey waters since last Wednesday.</p><p>Selangor Fire and Rescue Department deputy director Hafisham Mohd Noor said it received an emergency call at 5.38pm on April 7 about five containers having caught fire. The blaze then spread to the remaining containers today.</p><p>“So far, five containers have been completely extinguished, while sodium carbonate peroxyhydrate has been used to cool three more containers. Efforts are ongoing to put out the fire in three more containers,” he said in a statement today.</p><p>He said a total of 47 firemen from fire stations in Port Klang, North Port, Westport as well as the Malaysian Maritime Enforcement Agency (MMEA), Marine Police and Naval Special Forces (Paskal) were involved in the operation at 15 nautical miles of the Carey Island waters.</p><p>It was reported that the Interasia Catalyst cargo vessel sailing from Port Klang to Cochin in Kerala, India, was ordered to return to port after smoke was detected coming from several containers stacked on its deck. — Bernama</p>
            ]]></content:encoded>
                        <dc:creator></dc:creator>
                        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 17:57:22 +0800</pubDate>
            <dc:subject>selangor,bomba,pulau carey,fire and rescue department of malaysia,container fire</dc:subject>
        </item>
            </channel>
</rss>